<?xml version="1.0"?>
<mods xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" version="3.4" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Folds: Hueneme Canyon and Vicinity, California, 2012</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <name type="personal">
    <namePart>Ritchie, Andrew C.</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name type="personal">
    <namePart>Johnson, Samuel Y.</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name type="personal">
    <namePart>Clahan, Kevin B.</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name type="corporate">
    <namePart>Pacific Coastal and Marine Science Center</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name type="personal">
    <namePart>Golden, Nadine E.</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <typeOfResource>cartographic</typeOfResource>
  <typeOfResource>software, multimedia</typeOfResource>
  <genre authority="lcgft" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/genreForms/gf2011026297">Geospatial data</genre>
  <genre authority="rdacontent" valueURI="http://rdvocab.info/termList/RDAContentType/1001">cartographic dataset</genre>
  <originInfo>
    <publisher>Geological Survey (U.S.)</publisher>
    <place>
      <placeTerm type="text">Santa Cruz, California, US</placeTerm>
    </place>
    <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes">2012</dateIssued>
    <dateValid encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateValid>
  </originInfo>
  <language>
    <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <physicalDescription>
    <form>Shapefile</form>
    <extent>0.001</extent>
    <digitalOrigin>born digital</digitalOrigin>
  </physicalDescription>
  <subject>
    <cartographics>
      <scale>Scale not given.</scale>
      <projection>EPSG::32611</projection>
      <coordinates>(W 119&#xB0;19&#x2B9;7&#x2BA;--W 119&#xB0;11&#x2B9;14&#x2BA;/N 34&#xB0;13&#x2B9;20&#x2BA;--N 34&#xB0;3&#x2B9;50&#x2BA;)</coordinates>
    </cartographics>
  </subject>
  <abstract displayLabel="Abstract" lang="eng">This line shapefile represents geologic folds for Hueneme Canyon and the surrounding vicinity in California. The offshore map area is characterized by two major physiographic features: (1) the nearshore continental shelf and upper slope; and (2) Hueneme Canyon and parts of three smaller, unnamed submarine canyons incised into the shelf southeast of Hueneme Canyon. The nearshore, shelf, and slope are underlain by recent sediments and characterized by active sediment transport. Shelf and slope morphology and evolution result from drainage incision into deltaic sediments of the Oxnard plain during sea-level lowstand and subsequent sedimentation as sea level rose about 125 to 130 m over the last ~18,000 to 20,000 years (Lambeck and Chappell, 2001). This map area occurs in the southern part of the Western Transverse Ranges province, north of the California Continental Borderland (Fisher and others, 2009). Shelf deposits are deformed in the northernmost part of the map area by the west-trending Montalvo Fault and Anticline (Fisher and others, 2005). The Montalvo structures are part of a band of active deformation that includes the west-trending Oak Ridge Fault (Fisher and others, 2005), which extends into the offshore just a few km north of this map area. The Oak Ridge-Montalvo Fault Zone forms the southern boundary of the Ventura Basin and is considered an earthquake hazard because it extends along strike for about 130 km and appears to be the westward continuation of the fault system responsible for the 1994 M 6.7 Northridge earthquake. Only data for offshore map units are released digitally in this publication. For onshore geology (sheet 10) see Clahan (2003). The map was published in Scientific Investigations Map 3225. This layer is part of the USGS Data Series 781.</abstract>
  <abstract displayLabel="Purpose" lang="eng">In 2007, the California Ocean Protection Council initiated the California Seafloor Mapping Program (CSMP) to create a comprehensive seafloor map of high-resolution bathymetry, marine benthic habitats and geology within the 3-nautical-mile limit of California's State Waters. CSMP has divided coastal California into 110 map blocks, each to be published individually as United States Geological Survey Open-File Reports (OFRs) or Scientific Investigations Maps (SIMs) at a scale of 1:24,000. Maps display seafloor morphology and character, identify potential marine benthic habitats and illustrate both the seafloor geology and shallow (to about 100 m) subsurface geology. Data layers for bathymetry, bathymetric contours, acoustic backscatter, seafloor character, potential benthic habitat and offshore geology were created for each map block, as well as regional-scale data layers for sediment thickness, depth to transition, transgressive contours, isopachs, predicted distributions of benthic macro-invertebrates and visual observations of benthic habitat from video cruises over the entire state. This coverage can be used to aid in assessments and mitigation of geologic hazards and to provide sufficient geologic information for land-use and land-management decisions both onshore and offshore. These data are intended for science researchers, students, policy  makers, and the general public. This information is not intended for navigational purposes.The data can be used with geographic information systems (GIS) software to display geologic and oceanographic information. Additionally, this coverage can provide a geologic map for the public and geoscience community to aid in assessments and mitigation of geologic hazards in the coastal region and sufficient geologic information for land-use and land-management decisions both onshore and offshore. This information is not intended for navigational purposes.</abstract>
  <note displayLabel="Preferred citation" lang="eng">U.S. Geological Survey. (2013). Folds: Hueneme Canyon and Vicinity, California, 2012. California State Waters Map Series Data Catalog: U.S. Geological Survey Data Series 781. Available at: http://purl.stanford.edu/kw891hz5582.</note>
  <note displayLabel="Supplemental information">Map political location: Ventura County, California Compilation scale: 1:24,000 Base maps used are hillshades generated from IfSAR, LiDAR, and multibeam mapping both onshore and offshore (see sheet 2, SIM 3225 for more information). References Cited: Clahan, K.B., 2003, Geologic map of the Oxnard 7.5-minute quadrangle, Ventura Country, California: A Digital database, http://ngmdb.usgs.gov/Prodesc/proddesc_78382.htm California Geologic Survey, Preliminary Geologic Map, scale 1:24,000. Fisher, M.A., Greene, H.G., Normark, W.R., and Sliter, R.W., 2005, Neotectonics of the offshore Oak Ridge fault near Ventura, southern California: Bulletin of the Seismological Society of America, v. 95, p. 739-744. Fisher, M.A., Sorlien, C.C., and Sliter, R.W., 2009, Potential earthquake faults offshore southern California from the eastern Santa Barbara channel to Dana Point, in Lee, H.J., and Normark, W.R., eds., Earth science in the urban ocean--The Southern California Continental Borderland: Geological Society of America Special Paper 454, p. 271-290. Lambeck, K., and Chappell, J., 2001, Sea level change through the last glacial cycle: Science, v. 292, p. 679-686.</note>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html" lang="eng">Folds (Geology)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html" lang="eng">Ocean bottom</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html" lang="eng">Coasts</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic lang="eng" valueURI="http://sws.geonames.org/3687919/" authority="geonames" authorityURI="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#">California</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic lang="eng">Ventura County (Calif.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic lang="eng" valueURI="http://sws.geonames.org/8411083/" authority="geonames" authorityURI="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#">Pacific Ocean</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <temporal encoding="w3cdtf">2012</temporal>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="">Geoscientific Information</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="oceans">Oceans</topic>
  </subject>
  <location>
    <url>http://purl.stanford.edu/kw891hz5582</url>
  </location>
  <accessCondition type="useAndReproduction">This item is in the public domain. There are no restrictions on access or use.</accessCondition>
  <accessCondition type="useAndReproduction">This item is in the public domain. There are no restrictions on access or use.</accessCondition>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Stanford</recordContentSource>
    <recordIdentifier>edu.stanford.purl:kw891hz5582</recordIdentifier>
    <recordOrigin>This record was translated from ISO 19139 to MODS v.3 using an xsl transformation.</recordOrigin>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
  </recordInfo>
  <extension displayLabel="geo">
    <rdf:RDF xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml/3.2/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://purl.stanford.edu/kw891hz5582">
        <dc:format>application/x-esri-shapefile; format=Shapefile</dc:format>
        <dc:type>Dataset#LineString</dc:type>
        <gml:boundedBy>
          <gml:Envelope gml:srsName="EPSG:4326">
            <gml:lowerCorner>-119.31822 34.064135</gml:lowerCorner>
            <gml:upperCorner>-119.188411 34.220604</gml:upperCorner>
          </gml:Envelope>
        </gml:boundedBy>
        <dc:coverage rdf:resource="http://sws.geonames.org/3687919/" dc:language="eng" dc:title="California"/>
        <dc:coverage rdf:resource="" dc:language="eng" dc:title="Ventura County (Calif.)"/>
        <dc:coverage rdf:resource="http://sws.geonames.org/8411083/" dc:language="eng" dc:title="Pacific Ocean"/>
      </rdf:Description>
    </rdf:RDF>
  </extension>
<subject authority="EPSG" valueURI="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326" displayLabel="WGS84"><cartographics><scale>Scale not given.</scale><projection>EPSG::4326</projection><coordinates>W 119&#xB0;19&#x2B9;6&#x2BA;--W 119&#xB0;11&#x2B9;18&#x2BA;/N 34&#xB0;13&#x2B9;14&#x2BA;--N 34&#xB0;3&#x2B9;51&#x2BA;</coordinates></cartographics></subject><note displayLabel="WGS84 Cartographics">This layer is presented in the WGS84 coordinate system for web display purposes. Downloadable data are provided in native coordinate system or projection.</note></mods>
