<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" version="3.4" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Lakes of California, 2001</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <name type="corporate">
    <namePart>California. Department of Fish and Game. Marine Resources Region</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name type="corporate">
    <namePart>United States. Forest Service</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <typeOfResource>cartographic</typeOfResource>
  <typeOfResource>software, multimedia</typeOfResource>
  <genre authority="lcgft" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/genreForms/gf2011026297">Geospatial data</genre>
  <genre authority="rdacontent" valueURI="http://rdvocab.info/termList/RDAContentType/1001">cartographic dataset</genre>
  <originInfo>
    <publisher>California. Department of Fish and Game. Marine Resources Region</publisher>
    <place>
      <placeTerm type="text">Monterey, CA, US</placeTerm>
    </place>
    <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes">2001</dateIssued>
  </originInfo>
  <language>
    <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <physicalDescription>
    <form>Shapefile</form>
    <extent>15.203</extent>
    <digitalOrigin>born digital</digitalOrigin>
  </physicalDescription>
  <subject>
    <cartographics>
      <scale>Scale not given.</scale>
      <projection>Custom projection</projection>
      <coordinates>(W 124°28ʹ17ʺ--W 113°30ʹ49ʺ/N 42°1ʹ31ʺ--N 32°26ʹ21ʺ)</coordinates>
    </cartographics>
  </subject>
  <abstract displayLabel="Abstract" lang="eng">This polygon shapefile consists of over twenty-six thousand California lakes with the primary focus on those water bodies located in the High Sierras and California Cascades. The polygons represent lake shorelines with attributes including lake names and unique IDs. This layer is part of a collection of data created by the California Department of Fish and Game.</abstract>
  <abstract displayLabel="Purpose" lang="eng">The intended use of this data set is to assist with Fisheries Programs Management.</abstract>
  <note displayLabel="Preferred citation" lang="eng">U.S. Forest Service and California Department of Fish and Game. Marine Resources Region. (2001). Lakes of California, 2001. Department of Fish and Game. Available at: http://purl.stanford.edu/jd832sh5218.</note>
  <note displayLabel="Supplemental information">Converted to California Teale Albers NAD83 by the California Department of Fish and Game -- BEGIN ORIGINAL METADATA - THIS INFORMATION MAY NOT BE CURRENT -- CALIFORNIA DEPARTMENT OF FISH AND GAME GIS METADATA Lakes of California DATASET NAME: fpb_lakes METADATA FILE: fpb_lakes.txt METADATA DATE: April 5, 2001 DATASET DESCRIPTION: The fpb_lakes shapefile data set is an ArcView polygon feature type consisting of, over twenty-six thousand California water bodies, with primary focus on those water bodies located in the High Sierras and California Cascades. The polygons represent lake shorelines, with attributes including lake names and unique IDs. The intended use of this data set is to assist with fisheries programs management. ----- VITAL STATISTICS: Standard Teale Parameters Datum: NAD 27 Projection: Albers Units: Meters 1st Std. Parallel: 34 00 00 2nd Std. Parallel: 40 30 00 Longitude of Origin: -120 00 00 Latitude of Origin: 00 00 00 Sources: USGS 7.5' DRG quads, Lakes, Sn_lakes and Lakes_24k ArcView shapefile datasets Source Media: DRG Source Projection: Albers; databases: geographic coordinates Source Scales: 1:24,000 and 1:100,000 Capture Methods: Merge of data sets Lakes, Sn_lakes and Lakes_24k Conversion Software: ArcView ver. 3.2a Data Structure: Vector ArcView Feature Type: Polygon ArcView Precision: Single Polygons: 26,526 Data Set Size: 18.2 megabytes, as ArcView shapefile dataset Data Set Date: April 5, 2001 Data Set Last Modified: December 10,2001 ----- DATA DICTIONARY Structure of Table fpb_lakes.dbf ITEM NAME WIDTH TYPE N.DEC DESCRIPTION AREA 18 N 5 Polygon area in square meters PERIMETER 18 N 5 Polygon perimeter in meters LAKES_ID 10 N - Unique identifiers (ID) WATER 01 S - Water status in lake NAME 47 S - Lake name WRCBLAKES 04 N - Foreign key to lakes.dat GNIS_ID 20 S - GNIS name code D_source 16 S - Data source ----- DETAILED ITEM DESCRIPTIONS: Item WATER Code Meaning Y = lake with standing water I = island within lake N = dry lake __ Item NAME Lake names have Geographic Names Information System (GNIS) as their source. __ Item LAKES_ID Manually and sequentially assigned unique IDs starting with number two. __ Item WRCBLAKES Foreign key (relate item) from lakes.pat to INFO database lakes.dat, containing information on water quality and fisheries management. __ Item GNIS_ID USGS Geographic Names Information System (GNIS) code uniquely identifying the instance of the given lake name. This code is particularly useful for common lake names such as 'Bear Lake', 'Cold Lake', etc... __ Item D_SOURCE Code Meaning DFG_FPB = Originated from Lakes_24k dataset. Produced by Department of Fish and Game, Fisheries Programs Branch. DFG_ITB = Originated from Lakes dataset. Produced by Department of Fish and Game, Information Technology Branch. USDA_USFS = Originated from Sn_lakes dataset. Produced by the United States Department of Agriculture, United States Forest Service. ----- COVERAGE PROCESSING METHODOLOGY: The fpb_lakes shapefile data set was produced, using ArcView's GeoProcessing Wizard, by merging the data sets Lakes, Sn_lakes and Lakes_24k together. Lakes was the specified data set upon which Sn_lakes and Lakes_24k were merged. EDITS TO LAKES The edits made to Lakes.shp were removal of duplicate polygons. Polygons that were duplicates of polygons in Sn_lake.shp were removed. Deletion based upon the following criteria: Sn_lakes.shp was digitized at 1:24,000 and Lakes.shp was digitized at 1:100,000. The edits made to Lakes.dbf were removal of the fields Lakes_ and Lakes_id. Both fields were generated, populated and used by the original ARC/INFO lakes coverage. Lakes_id was re-created and re-populated in ArcView to represent unique IDs for the lakes. __ EDITS TO SN_LAKES The sn_lakes data set was obtained as an ARCINFO e00 file from the USDA Forest Service through the California Department of Forestry then converted to an ArcView shapefile. Edits made to sn_lakes.shp was the deletion of land polygons. Criteria for deletion was based upon the Sn_lakes.dbf. Records with 0 in the Water Field were removed. 0s indicated land. The edits made to sn_lakes.dbf were the deletion of Lakes_id, Lcode and Cff_code fields. Lakes_id was generated, populated and used by the original ARC/INFO sn_lakes coverage. Lakes_id was re-created and re-populated in ArcView to represent unique ids for the lakes. Lcode identified water body types, Lakes; Island; Reservoir; and River. This information was reclassified in the Water field. Cff_code was generated from the integer codes of Geometronics CFF files. The 'Name' field was created and populated using USGS 7.5' topographic quads. ----- DESCRIPTION AND LOCATION OF RELATED ORIGINAL DATA SETS: ABSTRACT fpb_lakes was produced by merging the data sets Lakes, Sn_Lakes and Lakes_24k together. The following is the original metadata for the three data sets. METADATA FOR LAKES \\applib1\gisdata\metadata\dfg\Lakes.txt __ METADATA FOR SN_LAKES \\fpb01gis\ddrive\data\meta\Sn_lakes.txt __ METADATA FOR LAKES_24K \\fpb01gis\ddrive\data\meta\Lakes_24k.txt ----- DATA CONTACT(S) Contact Name: Rod Gonzalez (CA Department of Fish and Game) Contact Voice Telephone: (916) 653-5232 Contact Electronic Mail Address: rgonzalez@dfg.ca.gov __ Metadata Security Information: Metadata Security Classification System: None Metadata Security Classification Description: None Last Modified: December 10, 2001 -- END ORIGINAL METADATA --</note>
  <note displayLabel="Use limitation">The intended use of this data set is to assist with Fisheries Programs Management.</note>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html" lang="eng">Lakes</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html" lang="eng">Bodies of water</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic lang="eng" valueURI="http://sws.geonames.org/3687919/" authority="geonames" authorityURI="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#">California</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <temporal encoding="w3cdtf">2001</temporal>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="inlandWaters">Inland Waters</topic>
  </subject>
  <location>
    <url>http://purl.stanford.edu/jd832sh5218</url>
  </location>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Stanford</recordContentSource>
    <recordIdentifier>edu.stanford.purl:jd832sh5218</recordIdentifier>
    <recordOrigin>This record was translated from ISO 19139 to MODS v.3 using an xsl transformation.</recordOrigin>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
  </recordInfo>
  <extension displayLabel="geo">
    <rdf:RDF xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml/3.2/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://purl.stanford.edu/jd832sh5218">
        <dc:format>application/x-esri-shapefile; format=Shapefile</dc:format>
        <dc:type>Dataset#Polygon</dc:type>
        <gml:boundedBy>
          <gml:Envelope gml:srsName="EPSG:4326">
            <gml:lowerCorner>-124.379541 32.547174</gml:lowerCorner>
            <gml:upperCorner>-114.138665 42.000237</gml:upperCorner>
          </gml:Envelope>
        </gml:boundedBy>
      </rdf:Description>
    </rdf:RDF>
  </extension>
  <subject authority="EPSG" valueURI="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326" displayLabel="WGS84">
    <cartographics>
      <scale>Scale not given.</scale>
      <projection>EPSG::4326</projection>
      <coordinates>W 124°22ʹ46ʺ--W 114°8ʹ19ʺ/N 42°1ʺ--N 32°32ʹ50ʺ</coordinates>
    </cartographics>
  </subject>
  <note displayLabel="WGS84 Cartographics">This layer is presented in the WGS84 coordinate system for web display purposes. Downloadable data are provided in native coordinate system or projection.</note>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>California Department of Fish and Wildlife GIS Maps &amp; Data</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <location>
      <url>https://purl.stanford.edu/fb282pw3043</url>
    </location>
    <typeOfResource collection="yes"/>
  </relatedItem>
  <accessCondition type="useAndReproduction">This item is in the public domain.  There are no restrictions on use.</accessCondition>
</mods>
