<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="3.7" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-7.xsd">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>ACS 5 Year Demographic Data by Place, 2008-2012</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>United States. Department of Housing and Urban Development</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">creator</roleTerm>
      </role>
    </name>
    <genre valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/genreForms/gf2011026297" authority="lcgft">Geospatial data</genre>
    <genre valueURI="http://rdvocab.info/termList/RDAContentType/1001" authority="rdacontent">cartographic dataset</genre>
    <typeOfResource>cartographic</typeOfResource>
    <typeOfResource>software, multimedia</typeOfResource>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form>Shapefile</form>
      <extent>170.946</extent>
      <digitalOrigin>born digital</digitalOrigin>
    </physicalDescription>
    <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <abstract lang="eng" displayLabel="Abstract">This polygon shapefile contains 5-year American Community Survey (ACS) estimates of demographic variables at the place level. The TIGER/Line Files are shapefiles and related database files (.dbf) that are an extract of selected geographic and cartographic information from the U.S. Census Bureaus Master Address File / Topologically Integrated Geographic Encoding and Referencing (MAF/TIGER) Database (MTDB). The MTDB represents a seamless national file with no overlaps or gaps between parts, however, each TIGER/Line File is designed to stand alone as an independent data set, or they can be combined to cover the entire nation. The TIGER/Line Files include both incorporated places (legal entities) and census designated places or CDPs (statistical entities). An incorporated place is established to provide governmental functions for a concentration of people as opposed to a minor civil division (MCD), which generally is created to provide services or administer an area without regard, necessarily, to population. Places always nest within a State, but may extend across county and county subdivision boundaries. An incorporated place usually is a city, town, village, or borough, but can have other legal descriptions. CDPs are delineated for the decennial census as the statistical counterparts of incorporated places. CDPs are delineated to provide data for settled concentrations of population that are identifiable by name, but are not legally incorporated under the laws of the State in which they are located. The boundaries for CDPs often are defined in partnership with State, local, and/or tribal officials and usually coincide with visible features or the boundary of an adjacent incorporated place or another legal entity. CDP boundaries often change from one decennial census to the next with changes in the settlement pattern and development; a CDP with the same name as in an earlier census does not necessarily have the same boundary. The only population/housing size requirement for CDPs for the 2010 Census is that they must contain some housing and population. The boundaries of all 2010 Census incorporated places are as of January 1, 2010 as reported through the Census Bureaus Boundary and Annexation Survey (BAS). The boundaries of all 2010 Census CDPs were delineated as part of the Census Bureaus Participant Statistical Areas Program (PSAP).The American Community Survey (ACS) 5 Year 2008-2012 demographic information is a subset of information available for download. Downloaded tables include: B01001 - Sex By Age, B03002 - Hispanic Or Latino Origin By Race, B11001 - Household Type (Including Living Alone), B11005 - Households By Presence Of People Under 18 Years By Household Type, B11006 - Households By Presence Of People 60 Years And Over By Household Type, B16005 - Nativity By Language Spoken At Home By Ability To Speak English For The Population 5 Years And Over, B25010 - Average Household Size Of Occupied Housing Units By Tenure and B15001 - Sex by Educational Attainment for the Population 18 Years and Over. Data is current as of 5/6/2015. released in 2012.</abstract>
    <abstract lang="eng" displayLabel="Purpose">This layer is intended for researchers, students, policy makers, and the general public for reference and mapping purposes, and may be used for basic applications such as viewing, querying, and map output production. This layer will provide a basemap for layers related to socio-political analysis, statistical enumeration and analysis, or to support graphical overlays and analysis with other spatial data. More advanced user applications may focus on demographics, urban and rural land use planning, socio-economic analysis and related areas (including defining boundaries, managing assets and facilities, integrating attribute databases with geographic features, spatial analysis, and presentation output.)</abstract>
    <note lang="eng" displayLabel="Preferred citation">United States. Department of Housing and Urban Development. (2015). ACS 5 Year Demographic Data by Place, 2008-2012. United States. Department of Housing and Urban Development. Available at http://purl.stanford.edu/hp504dh6313.</note>
    <note displayLabel="Supplemental information">To download additional demographic information, visit: http://www.census.gov/acs/www/.</note>
    <subject authority="lcsh" lang="eng">
      <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html">Population</topic>
    </subject>
    <subject authority="geonames" lang="eng">
      <geographic authority="geonames" authorityURI="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#" valueURI="http://sws.geonames.org/6252001/">United States</geographic>
    </subject>
    <subject>
      <temporal encoding="w3cdtf">2008-2012</temporal>
    </subject>
    <subject authority="ISO19115TopicCategory">
      <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="boundaries">Boundaries</topic>
    </subject>
    <subject authority="ISO19115TopicCategory">
      <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="society">Society</topic>
    </subject>
    <subject>
      <cartographics>
        <scale>Scale not given.</scale>
        <coordinates>W 176°42ʹ47ʺ--W 65°17ʹ27ʺ/N 71°20ʹ24ʺ--N 17°52ʹ53ʺ</coordinates>
      </cartographics>
    </subject>
    <subject displayLabel="WGS84" authority="EPSG" valueURI="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
      <cartographics>
        <projection>EPSG::4326</projection>
      </cartographics>
    </subject>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes">2015</dateIssued>
      <place>
        <placeTerm type="text">Washington D.C., US</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <publisher>United States. Department of Housing and Urban Development</publisher>
    </originInfo>
    <location>
      <url usage="primary display">https://purl.stanford.edu/hp504dh6313</url>
    </location>
    <recordInfo>
      <languageOfCataloging>
        <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
      <recordContentSource>Stanford</recordContentSource>
      <recordOrigin>This record was translated from ISO 19139 to MODS v.3 using an xsl transformation.</recordOrigin>
      <recordIdentifier>edu.stanford.purl:hp504dh6313</recordIdentifier>
    </recordInfo>
    <extension displayLabel="geo">
      <rdf:RDF xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml/3.2/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
        <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://purl.stanford.edu/hp504dh6313">
          <dc:format>application/x-esri-shapefile; format=Shapefile</dc:format>
          <dc:type>Dataset#Polygon</dc:type>
          <gml:boundedBy>
            <gml:Envelope gml:srsName="EPSG:4326">
              <gml:lowerCorner>-176.713098 17.881325</gml:lowerCorner>
              <gml:upperCorner>-65.290942 71.339946</gml:upperCorner>
            </gml:Envelope>
          </gml:boundedBy>
        </rdf:Description>
      </rdf:RDF>
    </extension>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development Maps and GIS Data</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <location>
        <url>https://purl.stanford.edu/wc590wy7435</url>
      </location>
      <typeOfResource collection="yes"/>
    </relatedItem>
    <accessCondition type="useAndReproduction">This item is in the public domain.  There are no restrictions on use.</accessCondition>
    <accessCondition type="copyright">This work is in the Public Domain, meaning that it is not subject to copyright.</accessCondition>
  </mods>
