<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="3.7" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-7.xsd">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Stream Floodways: Santa Cruz County, California, 2015</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart>Garcia, Paul</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">creator</roleTerm>
      </role>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart>Price, Matt</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">creator</roleTerm>
      </role>
    </name>
    <genre valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/genreForms/gf2011026297" authority="lcgft">Geospatial data</genre>
    <genre valueURI="http://rdvocab.info/termList/RDAContentType/1001" authority="rdacontent">cartographic dataset</genre>
    <typeOfResource>cartographic</typeOfResource>
    <typeOfResource>software, multimedia</typeOfResource>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form>Shapefile</form>
      <extent>4.516</extent>
      <digitalOrigin>born digital</digitalOrigin>
    </physicalDescription>
    <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <abstract lang="eng" displayLabel="Abstract">This polygon shapefile represents stream floodways in the County of Santa Cruz, California. A floodway is a channel of a river or other watercourse and the adjacent land areas that must be reserved in order to discharge the base flood without cumulatively increasing the water surface elevation more than a designated height. Communities must regulate development in these floodways to ensure that there are no increases in upstream flood elevations. For streams and other watercourses where the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) has provided Base Flood Elevations (BFEs), but no floodway has been designated, the community must review floodplain development on a case-by-case basis to ensure that increases in water surface elevations do not occur, or identify the need to adopt a floodway if adequate information is available. The Digital Flood Insurance Rate Map (DFIRM) Database depicts flood risk information and supporting data used to develop the risk data. The primary risk classifications used are the 1-percent-annual-chance flood event, the 0.2-percent-annual-chance flood event and areas of minimal flood risk. The DFIRM Database is derived from Flood Insurance Studies (FISs), previously published Flood Insurance Rate Maps (FIRMs), flood hazard analyses performed in support of the FISs and FIRMs and new mapping data where available. The FISs and FIRMs are published by the FEMA. The file is georeferenced to earth's surface using the UTM projection and coordinate system. The specifications for the horizontal control of DFIRM data files are consistent with those required for mapping at a scale of 1:12,000. This layer is part of a collection of GIS data created for Santa Cruz County, California.</abstract>
    <abstract lang="eng" displayLabel="Purpose">The Geographic Information Systems (GIS) Unit falls under the purview of the County of Santa Cruz Information Services Department. The GIS Unit serves all County departments and external customers and provides data on land, features and people of Santa Cruz County. Santa Cruz County encompasses 4 cities and approximately 265,000 people. This coverage can be used for basic applications such as viewing, querying and map output production, or to provide a basemap to support graphical overlays and analyses of geospatial data.</abstract>
    <note lang="eng" displayLabel="Preferred citation">County of Santa Cruz Information Services Department. (2015). Stream Floodways: Santa Cruz County, California, 2015. Santa Cruz County, California. Available at http://purl.stanford.edu/pj990pf6525.</note>
    <note displayLabel="Supplemental information">Federal Emergency Management Agency Special Flood Hazard Area: http://www.fema.gov/special-flood-hazard-area

Federal Emergency Management Agency Floodway: http://www.fema.gov/floodway

The FIRM is the basis for floodplain management, mitigation, and insurance activities for the National Flood Insurance Program (NFIP). Insurance applications include enforcement of the mandatory purchase requirement of the Flood Disaster Protection Act, which "... requires the purchase of flood insurance by property owners who are being assisted by Federal programs or by Federally supervised, regulated or insured agencies or institutions in the acquisition or improvement of land facilities located or to be located in identified areas having special flood hazards," Section 2 (b) (4) of the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973. In addition to the identification of Special Flood Hazard Areas (SFHAs), the risk zones shown on the FIRMs are the basis for the establishment of premium rates for flood coverage offered through the NFIP. The DFIRM Database presents the flood risk information depicted on the FIRM in a digital format suitable for use in electronic mapping applications. The DFIRM database is a subset of the Digital FIS database that serves to archive the information collected during the FIS.

The hardcopy FIRM and DFIRM and the accompanying FISs are the official designation of SFHAs and Base Flood Elevations (BFEs) for the NFIP. For the purposes of the NFIP, changes to the flood risk information published by FEMA may only be performed by FEMA and through the mechanisms established in the NFIP regulations (44 CFR Parts 59-78). These digital data are produced in conjunction with the hardcopy FIRMs and generally match the hardcopy map exactly. However the hardcopy flood maps and flood profiles are the authoritative documents for the NFIP. Acknowledgement of FEMA would be appreciated in products derived from these data. Native_Data_Set_Environment: Microsoft Windows 7 Version 6.1 (Build 7601) Service Pack 1; ESRI ArcGIS 10.0.3.3600</note>
    <note displayLabel="Use limitation">These data were compiled from many different sources; therefore, the accuracy of the individual layers varies significantly, and some layers do not align exactly with others. In the urban areas, data are generally accurate within five to ten feet of their true geographic coordinates, but in the rural areas, data may be accurate to only within three hundred feet. With these limitations, the County of Santa Cruz disclaims any responsibility for the accuracy or correctness of this data. This disclaimer is exclusive and in lieu of any warranties, fitness for particular purpose, and/or any other type of warranty, whether expressed or implied.</note>
    <note displayLabel="WGS84 Cartographics">This layer is presented in the WGS84 coordinate system for web display purposes. Downloadable data are provided in native coordinate system or projection.</note>
    <subject authority="lcsh" lang="eng">
      <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/">Floods</topic>
    </subject>
    <subject authority="lcsh" lang="eng">
      <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/">Floodplain management</topic>
    </subject>
    <subject authority="lcsh" lang="eng">
      <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/">Flood damage prevention</topic>
    </subject>
    <subject authority="lcsh" lang="eng">
      <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/">Flood insurance</topic>
    </subject>
    <subject lang="eng">
      <geographic>Santa Cruz County (Calif.)</geographic>
    </subject>
    <subject>
      <temporal encoding="w3cdtf">2015</temporal>
    </subject>
    <subject authority="ISO19115TopicCategory">
      <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="inlandWaters">Inland Waters</topic>
    </subject>
    <subject>
      <cartographics>
        <scale>Scale not given.</scale>
        <projection>EPSG::2227</projection>
        <coordinates>W 122°11ʹ48ʺ--W 121°38ʹ/N 37°12ʹ30ʺ--N 36°50ʹ50ʺ</coordinates>
        <coordinates>W 122°11ʹ33ʺ--W 121°38ʹ3ʺ/N 37°12ʹ9ʺ--N 36°51ʹ7ʺ</coordinates>
      </cartographics>
    </subject>
    <subject displayLabel="WGS84" authority="EPSG" valueURI="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
      <cartographics>
        <projection>EPSG::4326</projection>
      </cartographics>
    </subject>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes">2015</dateIssued>
      <dateValid encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateValid>
      <place>
        <placeTerm type="text">Santa Cruz, California, US</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <publisher>County of Santa Cruz Information Services Department</publisher>
    </originInfo>
    <location>
      <url usage="primary display">https://purl.stanford.edu/pj990pf6525</url>
    </location>
    <recordInfo>
      <languageOfCataloging>
        <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
      <recordContentSource>Stanford</recordContentSource>
      <recordOrigin>This record was translated from ISO 19139 to MODS v.3 using an xsl transformation.</recordOrigin>
      <recordIdentifier>edu.stanford.purl:pj990pf6525</recordIdentifier>
    </recordInfo>
    <extension displayLabel="geo">
      <rdf:RDF xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml/3.2/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
        <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://purl.stanford.edu/pj990pf6525">
          <dc:format>application/x-esri-shapefile; format=Shapefile</dc:format>
          <dc:type>Dataset#Polygon</dc:type>
          <gml:boundedBy>
            <gml:Envelope gml:srsName="EPSG:4326">
              <gml:lowerCorner>-122.192374 36.851956</gml:lowerCorner>
              <gml:upperCorner>-121.634065 37.202421</gml:upperCorner>
            </gml:Envelope>
          </gml:boundedBy>
        </rdf:Description>
      </rdf:RDF>
    </extension>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Santa Cruz County, California GIS Maps &amp; Data</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <location>
        <url>https://purl.stanford.edu/kn733hp1726</url>
      </location>
      <typeOfResource collection="yes"/>
    </relatedItem>
    <accessCondition type="useAndReproduction">This item is in the public domain.  There are no restrictions on use.</accessCondition>
    <accessCondition type="copyright">This work is in the Public Domain, meaning that it is not subject to copyright.</accessCondition>
  </mods>
