<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" version="3.4" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>California Salmonid Habitat Inventory: Russian River Basin, California, 1996-2002</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <name type="corporate">
    <namePart>Circuit Rider Productions</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <typeOfResource>cartographic</typeOfResource>
  <typeOfResource>software, multimedia</typeOfResource>
  <genre authority="lcgft" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/genreForms/gf2011026297">Geospatial data</genre>
  <genre authority="rdacontent" valueURI="http://rdvocab.info/termList/RDAContentType/1001">cartographic dataset</genre>
  <originInfo>
    <publisher>Circuit Rider Productions</publisher>
    <place>
      <placeTerm type="text">Windsor, California, US</placeTerm>
    </place>
    <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes">2002</dateIssued>
    <dateValid encoding="w3cdtf" point="start">1996</dateValid>
    <dateValid encoding="w3cdtf" point="end">2002</dateValid>
  </originInfo>
  <language>
    <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <physicalDescription>
    <form>Shapefile</form>
    <extent>0.474</extent>
    <digitalOrigin>born digital</digitalOrigin>
  </physicalDescription>
  <subject>
    <cartographics>
      <scale>Scale not given.</scale>
      <projection>EPSG::26910</projection>
      <coordinates>(W 123°20ʹ29ʺ--W 122°50ʹ38ʺ/N 39°11ʹ42ʺ--N 38°23ʹ12ʺ)</coordinates>
      <coordinates>(W 123°20ʹ29ʺ--W 122°50ʹ38ʺ/N 39°11ʹ42ʺ--N 38°23ʹ12ʺ)</coordinates>
    </cartographics>
  </subject>
  <abstract displayLabel="Abstract" lang="eng">This line shapefile represents the Russian River Watershed portion of the California Salmonid Habitat Inventory- a quantitative stream habitat survey focused on stream habitat restoration. Field biologists walk in-stream from confluence to headwaters of streams identifying pools, riffles, and flatwater areas as individual habitat units. Quantitative attributes include width, depth, substrate, bank vegetation, and slope to help identify restoration potential, stream health and monitoring potential.</abstract>
  <abstract displayLabel="Purpose" lang="eng">This data is inteded to aid in internal managment descisions regarding stream restoration projects and potential.</abstract>
  <note displayLabel="Preferred citation" lang="eng">Circuit Rider Productions and National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (2002). California Salmonid Habitat Inventory: Russian River Basin, California, 1996-2002. Circuit Rider Productions. Available at: http://purl.stanford.edu/cz715gw6055</note>
  <note displayLabel="Supplemental information">All stream surveys are dynamically segmented against 100k base hydrography routes.

The Dynamic Segmentation process is accomplished by 1)
Preparing a hydrography arc coverage with a unique numeric value
for each named stream 2) Ensuring flow direction for each stream
3) Building route/section topology for each stream 4) Preparing the
habitat table as linear event data with a)measure distances based
on field inputs and b)a unique key value for each named stream 5)
Calibrating routes based on field input from habitat table 6)
Displaying habitat tables in ArcView, converting to ArcView shapes
and distributing to field personnel.

1. DFG has obtained US Geologic Survey (USGS) Digital Line Graph
(DLG) 100,000 scale hydrography (See Appendix for Hydro Meta Data
and structure). In 1993, the US Environmental Protection Agency
(EPA) attached the River Reach File Version 3 (RF3) addressing
system to California's hydrographic coverage Arc Attribute Table
(.AAT). Arcs along the same named watercourse share a common
primary name code, or PNMCD. The unique key value for each stream
is the EPA national standard PNMCD.

2. Prior to building hydrography route/section topology, streams
must have consistent linear direction. I developed an Arc Macro
Language (AML) method for establishing direction of all streams
based on topology with no operator (See Appendix for flow.aml and
lake.aml). This process pathwalks each named stream from its
headwaters to its mouth and ensures all arcs point downstream
(including double lined streams). The DLG MINOR5 field is
populated with the arc numeric sequence of each stream from the
mouth.

3. I developed an ArcEdit AML which creates Route/Section
topology (See Appendix for mkroute.aml). The blanket Arc level
MAKEROUTE command will not ensure direction of all routes. The AML
creates one route for each unique PNMCD, in which the beginning
measure of the route is at the streams confluence (arc MINOR5 = 1
from flow.aml) and the ending measure is at the streams headwater.
The resulting Route Attribute Table (.RAT) has one record per
unique PNMCD. The resulting Section Attribute Table (.SEC) has one
record for arcs along each PNMCD.

4. Preparation of habitat data as event tables contains the
following processes: A) Insure the table has a properly populated
route relate item and B) create and populate measure items.

In some cases field personnel will not have the PNMCD value for
the surveyed stream, and will enter instead a latitude and
longitude of the stream confluence, the township range and section
number (called legal) and/or the stream name from the USGS 7.5
Minute Quadrangle. By cross referencing the quadrangle, lat/lon
coordinates, legal description or the stream name with the RF3
file, I find and enter the proper PNMCD value in the habitat table.
Each habitat table data will relate to the .RAT on the PNMCD.

The habitat table contains one record per habitat unit. The
LENGTH field is the length of each habitat unit, measured in feet.
Measure fields FROM, TO (for linear events), and LOCATION (for point
events) are added to the habitat table. The FROM field is equal
to the previous FROM value (0 for the first record). The TO field
is equal to the FROM field plus the LENGTH field. The LOCATION field
only populated when point event locations occur. While occurring
anywhere in a habitat unit, point events are surveyed with the same
length as a habitat unit. The LOCATION field equals half of the FROM
FROM field plus the TO field. Measure items are converted to meters,
the units of the hydrography coverage projection. Each record of a
habitat table will relate to the .SEC on the measure items FROM, TO
or LOCATION.

5. A point coverage for each survey, is made from each
tributary's confluence or road crossings and the end of the survey.
The end of survey point is digitized from a photocopied USGS
quadrangle. The points are attributed with the length to the mouth
taken from the habitat table, in meters. The Arc command
CALIBRATEROUTES uses the point coverage to correct the arc measured
distances with the field observed distances.

6. In Arcview, a view is added to a project and the hydrography
route topology added to the view. The habitat event table is added
to the project. With the view the active document, ADD EVENT THEME
from the VIEW menu is chosen. The Add Event Theme dialogue box is
populated, and the survey is displayed as an event theme. The
THEME CONVERT TO SHAPE menu choice converts the event theme to a
shape file. The shape file can be displayed and classified on any
or multiple fields in the Habitat Inventory. The process is
repeated for point events."</note>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html" lang="eng">Salmonid</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html" lang="eng">Restoration monitoring (Ecology)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic lang="eng" valueURI="http://sws.geonames.org/5397100/" authority="geonames" authorityURI="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#">Sonoma County (Calif.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic lang="eng" valueURI="http://sws.geonames.org/5372163/" authority="geonames" authorityURI="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#">Mendocino County (Calif.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic lang="eng">Russian River Watershed (Calif.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <temporal encoding="w3cdtf" point="start">1996</temporal>
    <temporal encoding="w3cdtf" point="end">2002</temporal>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="environment">Environment</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="inlandWaters">Inland Waters</topic>
  </subject>
  <location>
    <url>http://purl.stanford.edu/cz715gw6055</url>
  </location>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Stanford</recordContentSource>
    <recordIdentifier>edu.stanford.purl:cz715gw6055</recordIdentifier>
    <recordOrigin>This record was translated from ISO 19139 to MODS v.3 using an xsl transformation.</recordOrigin>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
  </recordInfo>
  <extension displayLabel="geo">
    <rdf:RDF xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml/3.2/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://purl.stanford.edu/cz715gw6055">
        <dc:format>application/x-esri-shapefile; format=Shapefile</dc:format>
        <dc:type>Dataset#LineString</dc:type>
        <gml:boundedBy>
          <gml:Envelope gml:srsName="EPSG:4326">
            <gml:lowerCorner>-123.341425 38.386997</gml:lowerCorner>
            <gml:upperCorner>-122.84551 39.194485</gml:upperCorner>
          </gml:Envelope>
        </gml:boundedBy>
      </rdf:Description>
    </rdf:RDF>
  </extension>
  <subject authority="EPSG" valueURI="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326" displayLabel="WGS84">
    <cartographics>
      <scale>Scale not given.</scale>
      <projection>EPSG::4326</projection>
      <coordinates>W 123°20ʹ29ʺ--W 122°50ʹ44ʺ/N 39°11ʹ40ʺ--N 38°23ʹ13ʺ</coordinates>
    </cartographics>
  </subject>
  <note displayLabel="WGS84 Cartographics">This layer is presented in the WGS84 coordinate system for web display purposes. Downloadable data are provided in native coordinate system or projection.</note>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Russian River watershed GIS</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <location>
      <url>https://purl.stanford.edu/zt526qk7324</url>
    </location>
    <typeOfResource collection="yes"/>
  </relatedItem>
  <accessCondition type="useAndReproduction">These data are licensed by Stanford Libraries and are available to Stanford University affiliates only. Affiliates are limited to current faculty, staff and students. Non affiliates seeking access should contact the publisher directly. These data may not be reproduced or used for any purpose without permission.</accessCondition>
</mods>
