<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="3.7" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-7.xsd">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Groundwater Subbasins: Santa Clara County, California, 2015</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Santa Clara Valley Water District (Calif.)</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">creator</roleTerm>
      </role>
    </name>
    <genre valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/genreForms/gf2011026297" authority="lcgft">Geospatial data</genre>
    <genre valueURI="http://rdvocab.info/termList/RDAContentType/1001" authority="rdacontent">cartographic dataset</genre>
    <typeOfResource>cartographic</typeOfResource>
    <typeOfResource>software, multimedia</typeOfResource>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form>Shapefile</form>
      <extent>0.192</extent>
      <digitalOrigin>born digital</digitalOrigin>
    </physicalDescription>
    <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <abstract lang="eng" displayLabel="Abstract">This polygon shapefile depicts boundares for Groundwater Subbasins in the County of Santa Clara, California. This includes distinctions between Califonia Department of Water Resources (DWR) groundwater subbasins (Santa Clara and Llagas), District groundwater areas (Santa Clara Plain, Coyote Valley and Llagas) and hydrographic units (Santa Clara Plain confined and recharge areas, Coyote Valley recharge area, Llagas confined and recharge areas and bedrock). A groundwater subbasin is a subdivision of a groundwater basin created by dividing the basin using geologic and hydrologic conditions or institutional boundaries.The Santa Clara and Llagas groundwater subbasin boundaries were extracted from DWR Bulletin 118 update 2003 GIS coverage. The Santa Clara Valley Water District manages an integrated water resources system that includes the supply of clean, safe water, flood protection and stewardship of streams on behalf of Santa Clara County's 1.8 million residents. This layer is part of a collection of GIS data for Santa Clara County, California.</abstract>
    <abstract lang="eng" displayLabel="Purpose">To identify portions of two groundwater basins as defined by the Califonia Department of Water Resources: the Santa Clara Valley (2-9) and the Hollister Valley Basins (3-3). This coverage can be used for basic applications such as viewing, querying, and map output production, or to provide a basemap to support graphical overlays and analyses of geospatial data.</abstract>
    <note lang="eng" displayLabel="Preferred citation">Santa Clara County, California. Planning Office. (2015). Groundwater Subbasins: Santa Clara County, California, 2015. Santa Clara County, Calif. Planning Office. Available at: http://purl.stanford.edu/vv585xg9890.</note>
    <note displayLabel="Supplemental information">The groundwater subbasins within the Santa Calara County managed by the District are the Santa Clara Subbasin (2-9.02) and the Llagas Subbasin (3-3.01). Delineation of groundwater subbasins is useful for knowing the extent of aquifer materials where groundwater recharge occurs, as well as basic information necessary to manage and protect the quantity and quality of groundwater resources. The Santa Clara Valley Water District (District) continually works to improve its understanding of the groundwater basins and subbasins boundaries.</note>
    <note displayLabel="Use limitation">None.These datasets were developed for use by the Santa Clara Valley Water District (SCVWD) for its internal purposes only, and were not designed or intended for general use by members of the public. SCVWD MAKES NO REPRESENTATION OR WARRANTY AS TO ITS ACCURACY, TIMELINESS, OR COMPLETENESS. SCVWD MAKES NO WARRANTY OF MERCHANTABILITY OR WARRANTY FOR FITNESS OF USE FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED, WITH RESPECT TO THESE PRODUCTS OR THE UNDERLYING DATA. Any user of this data, accepts same AS IS, WITH ALL FAULTS, and assumes all responsibility for the use thereof, and further covenants and agrees to defend, indemnify, and hold SCVWD harmless from and against all damage, loss, or liability arising from any use of this product, in consideration of SCVWD having made this information available.Independent verification of all data contained herein should be obtained by any user of these products, or the underlying data. SCVWD disclaims, and shall not be held liable for, any and all damage, loss, or liability, whether direct, indirect, or consequential, which arises or may arise from these products or the use thereof by any person or entity.</note>
    <note displayLabel="WGS84 Cartographics">This layer is presented in the WGS84 coordinate system for web display purposes. Downloadable data are provided in native coordinate system or projection.</note>
    <subject authority="lcsh" lang="eng">
      <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/">Hydrogeology</topic>
    </subject>
    <subject authority="lcsh" lang="eng">
      <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/">Aquifers</topic>
    </subject>
    <subject authority="lcsh" lang="eng">
      <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/">Groundwater recharge</topic>
    </subject>
    <subject authority="lcsh" lang="eng">
      <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/">Water table</topic>
    </subject>
    <subject authority="geonames" lang="eng">
      <geographic authority="geonames" authorityURI="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#" valueURI="http://sws.geonames.org/5393021/">Santa Clara County (Calif.)</geographic>
    </subject>
    <subject>
      <temporal encoding="w3cdtf">2015</temporal>
    </subject>
    <subject authority="ISO19115TopicCategory">
      <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="boundaries">Boundaries</topic>
    </subject>
    <subject authority="ISO19115TopicCategory">
      <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode">Geoscientific Information</topic>
    </subject>
    <subject>
      <cartographics>
        <scale>Scale not given.</scale>
        <projection>EPSG::2227</projection>
        <coordinates>W 122°11ʹ33ʺ--W 121°27ʹ47ʺ/N 37°29ʹ8ʺ--N 36°54ʹ50ʺ</coordinates>
        <coordinates>W 122°11ʹ29ʺ--W 121°27ʹ49ʺ/N 37°28ʹ44ʺ--N 36°55ʹ17ʺ</coordinates>
      </cartographics>
    </subject>
    <subject displayLabel="WGS84" authority="EPSG" valueURI="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
      <cartographics>
        <projection>EPSG::4326</projection>
      </cartographics>
    </subject>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes">2015</dateIssued>
      <dateValid encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateValid>
      <place>
        <placeTerm type="text">San Jose, California, US</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <publisher>Santa Clara Valley Water District (Calif.)</publisher>
    </originInfo>
    <location>
      <url usage="primary display">https://purl.stanford.edu/vv585xg9890</url>
    </location>
    <recordInfo>
      <languageOfCataloging>
        <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
      <recordContentSource>Stanford</recordContentSource>
      <recordOrigin>This record was translated from ISO 19139 to MODS v.3 using an xsl transformation.</recordOrigin>
      <recordIdentifier>edu.stanford.purl:vv585xg9890</recordIdentifier>
    </recordInfo>
    <extension displayLabel="geo">
      <rdf:RDF xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml/3.2/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
        <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://purl.stanford.edu/vv585xg9890">
          <dc:format>application/x-esri-shapefile; format=Shapefile</dc:format>
          <dc:type>Dataset#Polygon</dc:type>
          <gml:boundedBy>
            <gml:Envelope gml:srsName="EPSG:4326">
              <gml:lowerCorner>-122.191445 36.92139</gml:lowerCorner>
              <gml:upperCorner>-121.463745 37.478945</gml:upperCorner>
            </gml:Envelope>
          </gml:boundedBy>
        </rdf:Description>
      </rdf:RDF>
    </extension>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Santa Clara County, California GIS Maps &amp; Data</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <location>
        <url>https://purl.stanford.edu/zr514ds1803</url>
      </location>
      <typeOfResource collection="yes"/>
    </relatedItem>
    <accessCondition type="useAndReproduction">This item is in the public domain.  There are no restrictions on use.</accessCondition>
    <accessCondition type="copyright">This work is in the Public Domain, meaning that it is not subject to copyright.</accessCondition>
  </mods>
