<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="3.7" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-7.xsd">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Reducing Wildfire Risk to Forest Ecosystem Services, California, 2018</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>California. Department of Parks and Recreation</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">creator</roleTerm>
      </role>
    </name>
    <genre valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/genreForms/gf2011026297" authority="lcgft">Geospatial data</genre>
    <genre valueURI="http://rdvocab.info/termList/RDAContentType/1001" authority="rdacontent">cartographic dataset</genre>
    <typeOfResource>cartographic</typeOfResource>
    <typeOfResource>software, multimedia</typeOfResource>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form>Shapefile</form>
      <digitalOrigin>born digital</digitalOrigin>
    </physicalDescription>
    <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <abstract lang="eng" displayLabel="Abstract">This Priority Landscape (PL) prioritizes watersheds for potential treatment to reduce wildfire risk based on threats and assets to forested lands. Ranking: The ranking varies from 1 (least risk) to 5 (greatest risk). Lands such as conifer woodlands (e.g. juniper and pinyon-juniper), oak woodlands (blue oak woodland, valley oak woodland, coastal oak woodland, etc.), shrublands, grasslands, were not included. In addition, only forested lands with a fire return interval departure (FRID) of class 2 or greater were included. This ensures that the areas most in need of treatment to restore natural fire regimes and improve ecological functions are prioritized. Assets: Surface water value: Watersheds (HUC12s) were ranked based on surface drinking water value from the USDA Forest Service's Forests to Faucet data, https://www.fs.fed.us/ecosystemservices/FS_Efforts/forests2faucets.shtml Carbon storage: Estimated amount of carbon in the forest that is in living trees above the ground was spatially imputed into a GIS layer from Forest Service FIA data by Wilson et al. (2013) using a gradient nearest neighbor (GNN) technique. See Wilson, B.T., C.W. Woodall, and D.M. Griffith, Imputing forest carbon stock estimates from inventory plots to a nationally continuous coverage. Carbon Balance and Management, 2013. 8(1): p. 15. Standing timber: Shows the estimated commercial timber volume on lands available for harvesting. Standing Timber was was primarily derived from LEMMA Structure Maps (https://lemma.forestry.oregonstate.edu/data/structure-maps) that also used Forest Service FIA data and a GNN methodology (2012 vintage). LEMMA commercial timber volume was reduced for areas of high fire severity burns through 2017 (from FRAP), BAER imagery for areas of high severity wildfires that have occurred in 2018 (from:https://fsapps.nwcg.gov/afm/baer/download.php), and Aerial Detection Survey data of areas of high tree mortality (also subsequent to 2012). Lands not available for timber harvest were removed, including southern California and South Central Coast counties with no viable timber processing facilities. Site quality: This shows the productivity of timberland, based upon potential volume of wood (i.e. cubic feet) that can be produced per acre in a year. Site Class GIS data was produced by Wilson from Forest Service FIA data (using the same methods as for the Carbon storage layer), based upon FIA attribute SITECLCD – site productivity class code. It shows the potential timber volume produced at culmination of mean annual increment, in the standard classes used by the USFS. Large trees: Derived from FRAP vegetation layer FVEG15 (WHRSIZE), which in turn (for this attribute) came from CALVEG data of the USFS. Tree size class scores were 1=(6-11" DBH), 3=(11-24" DBH), and 5=(over 24" DBH). Threats: Fire threat: FRAP fire threat data (fthrt14_2) was derived from a combination of FRAP surface fuels data and large fire probability from the Fire Simulation (FSim) system developed by the US Forest Service Missoula, Montana Fire Sciences Laboratory. Fire Return Interval Departure (FRID): FRID shows the deviation from historic averages of fire occurrence. FRID from USFS Region 5 was used to prioritize areas most in need of treatment. FRID scores of 2, 3, and 4 were assigned scores of 1, 3, and 5 respectively. Composite Ranks: All assets were combined and the result ranked from 1 to 5 to derive a composite asset. Likewise, all threats were combined the results ranked from 1 to 5 to create a composite threat. The composite asset layer and composite threat ranks were then combined and classified to a final priority landscape rank for each 30m pixel. Watershed Ranking: A zonal mean of pixel ranks was then calculated for HUC12 watersheds (the smallest consistently delineated watershed, average approximately 24,000 acres). The end result is that each watershed is ranked from 1 (lowest threat) to 5 (highest threat) based on the combination of assets and threats and averaged by watershed. Watershed boundaries used were from the National Hydrography Dataset Watershed Boundary Dataset. This dataset was developed in 2018 to support the California Assessment of Forest and Rangelands.</abstract>
    <note lang="eng" displayLabel="Preferred citation">California. Department of Forestry and Fire Protection. (2018). Reducing Wildfire Risk to Forest Ecosystem Services, California, 2018. California. Department of Forestry and Fire Protection. Available at: https://purl.stanford.edu/nw945zv2996</note>
    <note displayLabel="WGS84 Cartographics">This layer is presented in the WGS84 coordinate system for web display purposes. Downloadable data are provided in native coordinate system or projection.</note>
    <subject authority="lcsh" lang="eng">
      <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html">Fire risk assessment</topic>
    </subject>
    <subject authority="geonames" lang="eng">
      <geographic authority="geonames" authorityURI="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#" valueURI="http://sws.geonames.org/3687919/">California</geographic>
    </subject>
    <subject>
      <temporal encoding="w3cdtf">2018</temporal>
    </subject>
    <subject authority="ISO19115TopicCategory">
      <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="boundaries">Boundaries</topic>
    </subject>
    <subject>
      <cartographics>
        <scale>Scale not given.</scale>
        <projection>Custom projection</projection>
        <coordinates>W 124°30ʹ22ʺ--W 113°29ʹ55ʺ/N 42°4ʹ8ʺ--N 32°25ʹ25ʺ</coordinates>
      </cartographics>
    </subject>
    <subject displayLabel="WGS84" authority="EPSG" valueURI="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
      <cartographics>
        <projection>EPSG::4326</projection>
      </cartographics>
    </subject>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes">2018</dateIssued>
      <publisher>California. Department of Parks and Recreation</publisher>
    </originInfo>
    <location>
      <url usage="primary display">https://purl.stanford.edu/nw945zv2996</url>
    </location>
    <recordInfo>
      <languageOfCataloging>
        <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
      <recordContentSource>Stanford</recordContentSource>
      <recordOrigin>This record was translated from ISO 19139 to MODS v.3 using an xsl transformation.</recordOrigin>
      <recordIdentifier>edu.stanford.purl:nw945zv2996</recordIdentifier>
    </recordInfo>
    <extension displayLabel="geo">
      <rdf:RDF xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml/3.2/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
        <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://purl.stanford.edu/nw945zv2996">
          <dc:format>image/tiff; format=GeoTIFF</dc:format>
          <dc:type>Dataset#Raster</dc:type>
          <gml:boundedBy>
            <gml:Envelope gml:srsName="EPSG:4326">
              <gml:lowerCorner>-124.5061084 32.4235871</gml:lowerCorner>
              <gml:upperCorner>-113.4984742 42.0688452</gml:upperCorner>
            </gml:Envelope>
          </gml:boundedBy>
        </rdf:Description>
      </rdf:RDF>
    </extension>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>California Department of Forestry and Fire Protection, GIS Maps &amp; Data</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <location>
        <url>https://purl.stanford.edu/ng146rv3289</url>
      </location>
      <typeOfResource collection="yes"/>
    </relatedItem>
    <accessCondition type="useAndReproduction">The user will cite the Department of Forestry and Fire Protection as the original source of the maps, but will clearly denote cases where the original maps have been updated, modified, or in any way altered from the original condition. The State of California and the Department of Forestry and Fire Protection make no representations or warranties regarding the accuracy of data or maps. Neither the State nor the Department shall be liable under any circumstances for any direct, special, incidental, or consequential damages with respect to any claim by any user or third party on account of or arising from the use of data or maps.</accessCondition>
  </mods>
