<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="3.7" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-7.xsd">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Periodic Adult Distribution: California Scorpionfish, California, 2001</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>California. Department of Fish and Game. Marine Resources Region</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">creator</roleTerm>
      </role>
    </name>
    <genre valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/genreForms/gf2011026297" authority="lcgft">Geospatial data</genre>
    <genre valueURI="http://rdvocab.info/termList/RDAContentType/1001" authority="rdacontent">cartographic dataset</genre>
    <typeOfResource>cartographic</typeOfResource>
    <typeOfResource>software, multimedia</typeOfResource>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form>Shapefile</form>
      <extent>0.831</extent>
      <digitalOrigin>born digital</digitalOrigin>
    </physicalDescription>
    <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <abstract lang="eng" displayLabel="Abstract">This polyline shapefile depicts periodic distribution for adult California Scorpionfish (Scorpaena guttata). The process of creating this shapefile included creating contour lines, in 5-meter intervals, from bathymetry lines. Depth ranges were taken from four different references (see Resource Details Supplemental Information). After the depth range between which this species is most common was determined, they were rounded to the closest 5-meter interval. The deepest and shallowest shapefile lines were connected by a line at the northern end and southern end (determined by their geographical range from north to south). This shapefile was then converted to polygon. The goal of this shapefile was to provide a range in which this species could occur, given that their habitat is present.</abstract>
    <abstract lang="eng" displayLabel="Purpose">This coverage displays the geographic range of select Pacific Ocean fish species.</abstract>
    <note lang="eng" displayLabel="Preferred citation">California Department of Fish and Game. (2006). Periodic Adult Distribution: California Scorpionfish, California, 2001. Biogeographic Data Branch. Available at: http://purl.stanford.edu/jt797hs8906</note>
    <note displayLabel="Supplemental information">Converted to California Teale Albers NAD 83 by the California Department of Fish and Game, Marine GIS --BEGIN ORIGINAL METADATA - THIS INFORMATION MAY NOT BE CURRENT-- California Department of Fish and Game Marine Region GIS Metadata Shapefile Name: blkyl-rf-adco.shp Metadata File: blkyl-rf-adco.txt Metadata Date: April 19, 2001 Shapefile Description This shapefile contains the most common distribution for adults. The process of creating this shapefile included creating contour lines, in 5 meter intervals, from bathymetry lines. Depth ranges were taken from four references (see below). After the depth range between which this species is most common was determined, they were rounded to the closest 5 meter interval. The deepest and shallowest shapefile lines were connected by a line at the northern end and southern end (determined by their geographical range from north to south). This shapefile was then converted to polygon. The goal of this shapefile was to provide a range in which this species could occur, given that their habitat is present. References for North and South extent as well as depth ranges: Eschmeyer, W.N. and E.S. Herald. 1983. A field guide to Pacific coast fishes of North America. Houghton Mifflin Co., Boston, MA. 336 p. Love, M. 1996. Probably More Than You Want To Know About The Fishes Of The Pacific Coast. Really Big Press, Santa Barbara, California, 381 p. Love, M.S., L. Thorsteinson, C.W. Mecklenburg, and T.A. Mecklenburg. In Preparation (January 2000). A checklist of marine and estuarine fishes of the Northeast Pacific, from Alaska to Baja California. National Biological Service. Located at website http://id-www.ucsb.edu/lovelab/home.html Miller, D.J. and R.N. Lea. 1972. Guide to the coastal marine fishes of California. California Department of Fish and Game, Fish Bulletin 157, 249 p. Vital Statistics Datum: NAD27 Projection: Albers (standard Teale parameters) Units: Meters 1st Std. Parallel: 34 00 00 N 2nd Std. Parallel: 40 30 00 N False Easting: 0.0 False Northing: -4,000,000 Attributes Table Structure of blkyl-rf-adco.dbf Number of records: 13 Item Name Type Description Shape S point shape feature Area N calculated area for polygon Perimeter N calculated perimeter Hectares N hectares for polygon Name S common name for species Sci. Name S scientific name for species Range S common range for adults of this species depth range S gives the shallow and deep depths in meters north to south S gives the north and south extent for this species DFG Marine Region GIS Contacts Nancy Wright California Department of Fish and Game GIS Analyst Marine Region 20 Lower Ragsdale Drive Monterey, CA 93940 (831) 649-2942 nmwright@dfg.ca.gov GIS Technical Contact Colleena Perez California Department of Fish and Game Scientific Aid Marine Region 20 Lower Ragsdale Drive Monterey, CA 93940 (831) 649-7143 cperez@dfg.ca.gov --END ORIGINAL METADATA--</note>
    <note displayLabel="Use limitation">None.</note>
    <note displayLabel="WGS84 Cartographics">This layer is presented in the WGS84 coordinate system for web display purposes. Downloadable data are provided in native coordinate system or projection.</note>
    <subject authority="lcsh" lang="eng">
      <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html">Marine habitats</topic>
    </subject>
    <subject authority="lcsh" lang="eng">
      <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html">Fishes--Habitat</topic>
    </subject>
    <subject authority="lcsh" lang="eng">
      <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html">Fishes--Home range</topic>
    </subject>
    <subject authority="lcsh" lang="eng">
      <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html">Fishes</topic>
    </subject>
    <subject authority="lcsh" lang="eng">
      <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html">Coasts</topic>
    </subject>
    <subject authority="geonames" lang="eng">
      <geographic authority="geonames" authorityURI="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#" valueURI="http://sws.geonames.org/3687919/">California</geographic>
    </subject>
    <subject authority="geonames" lang="eng">
      <geographic authority="geonames" authorityURI="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#" valueURI="http://sws.geonames.org/8411083/">Pacific Ocean</geographic>
    </subject>
    <subject>
      <temporal encoding="w3cdtf">2001</temporal>
    </subject>
    <subject authority="ISO19115TopicCategory">
      <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="biota">Biology and Ecology</topic>
    </subject>
    <subject authority="ISO19115TopicCategory">
      <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="oceans">Oceans</topic>
    </subject>
    <subject>
      <cartographics>
        <scale>Scale not given.</scale>
        <projection>Custom projection</projection>
        <coordinates>W 122°44ʺ--W 117°4ʹ53ʺ/N 36°59ʹ3ʺ--N 32°39ʹ53ʺ</coordinates>
        <coordinates>W 122°44ʺ--W 117°14ʹ14ʺ/N 36°58ʹ4ʺ--N 32°39ʹ54ʺ</coordinates>
      </cartographics>
    </subject>
    <subject displayLabel="WGS84" authority="EPSG" valueURI="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
      <cartographics>
        <projection>EPSG::4326</projection>
      </cartographics>
    </subject>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes">2001</dateIssued>
      <dateValid encoding="w3cdtf">2001</dateValid>
      <place>
        <placeTerm type="text">Monterey, CA, US</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <publisher>California. Department of Fish and Game. Marine Resources Region</publisher>
    </originInfo>
    <location>
      <url usage="primary display">https://purl.stanford.edu/jt797hs8906</url>
    </location>
    <recordInfo>
      <languageOfCataloging>
        <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
      <recordContentSource>Stanford</recordContentSource>
      <recordOrigin>This record was translated from ISO 19139 to MODS v.3 using an xsl transformation.</recordOrigin>
      <recordIdentifier>edu.stanford.purl:jt797hs8906</recordIdentifier>
    </recordInfo>
    <extension displayLabel="geo">
      <rdf:RDF xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml/3.2/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
        <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://purl.stanford.edu/jt797hs8906">
          <dc:format>application/x-esri-shapefile; format=Shapefile</dc:format>
          <dc:type>Dataset#LineString</dc:type>
          <gml:boundedBy>
            <gml:Envelope gml:srsName="EPSG:4326">
              <gml:lowerCorner>-122.01217 32.664933</gml:lowerCorner>
              <gml:upperCorner>-117.23711 36.967881</gml:upperCorner>
            </gml:Envelope>
          </gml:boundedBy>
        </rdf:Description>
      </rdf:RDF>
    </extension>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>California Department of Fish and Wildlife GIS Maps &amp; Data</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <location>
        <url>https://purl.stanford.edu/fb282pw3043</url>
      </location>
      <typeOfResource collection="yes"/>
    </relatedItem>
    <accessCondition type="useAndReproduction">This item is in the public domain.  There are no restrictions on use.</accessCondition>
    <accessCondition type="copyright">This work is in the Public Domain, meaning that it is not subject to copyright.</accessCondition>
  </mods>
