<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" version="3.4" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Highway Rail Crossings, California, 2010</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <name type="corporate">
    <namePart>California. Department of Transportation</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <typeOfResource>cartographic</typeOfResource>
  <typeOfResource>software, multimedia</typeOfResource>
  <genre authority="lcgft" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/genreForms/gf2011026297">Geospatial data</genre>
  <genre authority="rdacontent" valueURI="http://rdvocab.info/termList/RDAContentType/1001">cartographic dataset</genre>
  <originInfo>
    <publisher>California. Department of Transportation</publisher>
    <place>
      <placeTerm type="text">Sacramento, US</placeTerm>
    </place>
    <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes">2013</dateIssued>
  </originInfo>
  <language>
    <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <physicalDescription>
    <form>Shapefile</form>
    <extent>0.229</extent>
    <digitalOrigin>born digital</digitalOrigin>
  </physicalDescription>
  <subject>
    <cartographics>
      <scale>Scale not given.</scale>
      <projection>EPSG::4269</projection>
      <coordinates>(W -124.223518--W -114.37174/N 42.004555--N 32.554916)</coordinates>
    </cartographics>
  </subject>
  <abstract displayLabel="Abstract" lang="eng">This point shapefile contains the locations of highway railroad crossings in California. These data were created using the California Public Utilities Commission (PUC) inventory database of highway-rail crossings. The PUC data contains a [grade] attribute that allows for the isolation of at-grade crossings. There are 7,719 at-grade records in the most recent PUC file available. The PUC data also includes a crossing numbering system that should be maintained as part of the development of this feature to facilitate easy update and linkage to subsequent releases. There are approximately 10,000 open crossings included in the state inventory as of November 2010. The fields included in this table are copied directly from the CPUC data set without any changes. This layer is part of a collection of GIS data created by the California Department of Transportation (Caltrans).</abstract>
  <abstract displayLabel="Purpose" lang="eng">This dataset is intended for researchers, students, and policy makers for reference and mapping purposes, and may be used for basic applications such as viewing, querying, and map output production, or to provide a basemap to support graphical overlays and analysis with other spatial data.</abstract>
  <note displayLabel="Preferred citation" lang="eng">California Department of Transportation. (2013). Highway Rail Crossings, California, 2010. California Department of Transportation. Available at http://purl.stanford.edu/pt563kw3303.</note>
  <note displayLabel="Use limitation">This is Category I data. Category I data are public domain and available to share with Caltrans partners. Caltrans makes no representation about the suitability, reliability, availability, timeliness, or accuracy of its GIS data for any purpose. The GIS data and information are provided "as is" without warranty of any kind. Use of the data should be limited to informational and preliminary study purposes only. Caltrans shall not be held liable by users of the data, or by any other party, for any loss or damages, consequential or otherwise, including but not limited to time, money, or goodwill, arising from the use, operation or modification of the data. For planning purposes only. The Rail Database is intended for high level planning purposes and is a point in time reporting of estimated current conditions and forecast of future conditions. While every effort has been made to ensure accuracy of reported data, the Database is not intended for detailed service or facility planning. Such planning requires in-depth site analysis and field confirmation of actual conditions.</note>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html" lang="eng">Highway-railroad grade crossings</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html" lang="eng">Railroads</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic lang="eng" valueURI="http://sws.geonames.org/3687919/" authority="geonames" authorityURI="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#">California</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <temporal encoding="w3cdtf">2010</temporal>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="transportation">Transportation</topic>
  </subject>
  <location>
    <url>http://purl.stanford.edu/pt563kw3303</url>
  </location>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Stanford</recordContentSource>
    <recordIdentifier>edu.stanford.purl:pt563kw3303</recordIdentifier>
    <recordOrigin>This record was translated from ISO 19139 to MODS v.3 using an xsl transformation.</recordOrigin>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
  </recordInfo>
  <extension displayLabel="geo">
    <rdf:RDF xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml/3.2/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://purl.stanford.edu/pt563kw3303">
        <dc:format>application/x-esri-shapefile; format=Shapefile</dc:format>
        <dc:type>Dataset#Point</dc:type>
        <gml:boundedBy>
          <gml:Envelope gml:srsName="EPSG:4326">
            <gml:lowerCorner>-124.223518 32.554916</gml:lowerCorner>
            <gml:upperCorner>-114.37174 42.004555</gml:upperCorner>
          </gml:Envelope>
        </gml:boundedBy>
      </rdf:Description>
    </rdf:RDF>
  </extension>
  <subject authority="EPSG" valueURI="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326" displayLabel="WGS84">
    <cartographics>
      <scale>Scale not given.</scale>
      <projection>EPSG::4326</projection>
      <coordinates>(W -124.223518--W -114.37174/N 42.004555--N 32.554916)</coordinates>
    </cartographics>
  </subject>
  <note displayLabel="WGS84 Cartographics">This layer is presented in the WGS84 coordinate system for web display purposes. Downloadable data are provided in native coordinate system or projection.</note>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>California Department of Transportation GIS Maps &amp; Data</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <location>
      <url>https://purl.stanford.edu/sb381ch4421</url>
    </location>
    <typeOfResource collection="yes"/>
  </relatedItem>
  <accessCondition type="useAndReproduction">This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.

This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU General Public License for more details. http://www.gnu.org/licenses.</accessCondition>
</mods>
