<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" version="3.4" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Medical Service Study Areas, California, 2010</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <name type="corporate">
    <namePart>California. Office of Statewide Health Planning and Development</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <typeOfResource>cartographic</typeOfResource>
  <typeOfResource>software, multimedia</typeOfResource>
  <genre authority="lcgft" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/genreForms/gf2011026297">Geospatial data</genre>
  <genre authority="rdacontent" valueURI="http://rdvocab.info/termList/RDAContentType/1001">cartographic dataset</genre>
  <originInfo>
    <publisher>California. Office of Statewide Health Planning and Development</publisher>
    <place>
      <placeTerm type="text">Sacramento, US</placeTerm>
    </place>
    <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes">2010</dateIssued>
    <edition>MSSA_ACS2010v2</edition>
  </originInfo>
  <language>
    <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <physicalDescription>
    <form>Shapefile</form>
    <extent>21.746</extent>
    <digitalOrigin>born digital</digitalOrigin>
  </physicalDescription>
  <subject>
    <cartographics>
      <scale>Scale not given.</scale>
      <projection>Custom projection</projection>
      <coordinates>(W 124°30ʹ22ʺ--W 113°29ʹ54ʺ/N 42°4ʹ7ʺ--N 32°25ʹ25ʺ)</coordinates>
    </cartographics>
  </subject>
  <abstract displayLabel="Abstract" lang="eng">This polygon shapefile represents medical service study areas (MSSA) in California for 2010. MSSAs are the defined geographic analysis unit for the Office of Statewide Health Planning and Development (OSHPD). MSSAs are a principal component for display of large data bases through OSHPD's and State of California's Geographic Information Systems. MSSAs have the potential for assisting in needs assessment, health planning, and health policy development. MSSA's are reproduced on the decadal census and the boundaries are formally approved by the Health Manpower Policy Commission. Moreover, the US Department of Health and Human Services, Health Resources Serviced Administration (HRSA) formally recognizes California MSSA's as the Rational Service Area (RSA) for medical service for California.The 2007 MSSA layer (developed during July 2009 - July 2010) is an update to the 2005 version and represents the boundaries constructed following the census. The MSSA layer is the unique MSSA boundaries composed of aggregated census tracts. This layer is created by dissolving all census tracts on a common MSSA Name/ID. MSSA's are maintained by OSHPD and used by multiple agencies to administer a variety of state and federal health-related programs. This represents the final MSSA Reconfiguration based on U.S. Census 2010, public meetings held throughout California with stakeholder input and approved by the California Healthcare Workforce Policy Commission on May 29, 2013. Revised October, 2013 to add Farallon Island in San Francisco County, CT 9804.01 to MSSA 162d. This layer is part of the Healthcare Atlas of California.</abstract>
  <abstract displayLabel="Purpose" lang="eng">The MSSA ACS layer is an update using 2010 U.S. Census data.   This is an update to geometries and demographics. The Medical Service Study Area (MSSA) Census Tract Detail polygon layer represents all California census tract boundaries used in the construction based on U.S. Census Tracts 2010.  Each of the state's 8,035 census tracts (shoreline buffer census tracts were removed) was assigned to a medical service study area, as identified in this data layer.  The MSSA Census Tract Detail data is aggregated by OSHPD, to create this MSSA data layer.
This represents the final MSSA Reconfiguration based on U.S. Census 2010 and public meetings held throughout California.</abstract>
  <note displayLabel="Preferred citation" lang="eng">California Office of Statewide Health Planning and Development. (2010). Medical Service Study Areas, California, 2010. California Office of Statewide Health Planning and Development. Available at: http://purl.stanford.edu/ph637gq9746.</note>
  <note displayLabel="Supplemental information">Source of update: American Community Survey 5 year 2006-2010 data for poverty. For source tables refer to InfoUSA update procedural documentation. The 2012 MSSA Detail layer was developed to update fields affected by population change. The American Community Survey 5 year 2006-2010 population data pertaining to total, in households, race, ethnicity, age, and poverty was used in the update. The 2012 MSSA Census Tract Detail map layer was developed to support geographic information systems (GIS) applications, representing 2010 census tract geography that is the foundation of 2012 medical service study area (MSSA) boundaries. ***This version is the finalized MSSA reconfiguration boundaries based on the US Census Bureau 2010 Census. In 1976 Garamendi Rural Health Services Act, required the development of a geographic framework for determining which parts of the state were rural and which were urban, and for determining which parts of counties and cities had adequate health care resources and which were "medically underserved". Thus, sub-city and sub-county geographic units called "medical service study areas [MSSAs]" were developed, using combinations of census-defined geographic units, established following General Rules promulgated by a statutory commission. After each subsequent census the MSSAs were revised.In the scheduled revisions that followed the 1990 census, community meetings of stakeholders (including county officials, and representatives of hospitals and community health centers) were held in larger metropolitan areas. The meetings were designed to develop consensus as how to draw the sub-city units so as to best display health care disparities.The importance of involving stakeholders was heightened in 1992 when the United States Department of Health and Human Services' Health and Resources Administration entered a formal agreement to recognize the state-determined MSSAs as "rational service areas" for federal recognition of "health professional shortage areas" and "medically underserved areas".After the 2000 census, two innovations transformed the process, and set the stage for GIS to emerge as a major factor in health care resource planning in California. First, the Office of Statewide Health Planning and Development [OSHPD], which organizes the community stakeholder meetings and provides the staff to administer the MSSAs, entered into an Enterprise GIS contract. Second, OSHPD authorized at least one community meeting to be held in each of the 58 counties, a significant number of which were wholly rural or frontier counties. For populous Los Angeles County, 11 community meetings were held.As a result, health resource data in California are collected and organized by 541 geographic units. The boundaries of these units were established by community healthcare experts, with the objective of maximizing their usefulness for needs assessment purposes. The most dramatic consequence was introducing a data simultaneously displayed in a GIS format.A two-person team, incorporating healthcare policy and GIS expertise, conducted the series of meetings, and supervised the development of the 2000-census configuration of the MSSAs. 
MSSA Configuration Guidelines (General Rules):- Each MSSA is composed of one or more complete census tracts.- As a general rule, MSSAs are deemed to be "rational service areas [RSAs]" for purposes of designating health professional shortage areas [HPSAs], medically underserved areas [MUAs] or medically underserved populations [MUPs].- MSSAs will not cross county lines.- To the extent practicable, all census-defined places within the MSSA are within 30 minutes travel time to the largest population center within the MSSA, except in those circumstances where meeting this criterion would require splitting a census tract.- To the extent practicable, areas that, standing alone, would meet both the definition of an MSSA and a Rural MSSA, should not be a part of an Urban MSSA.- Any Urban MSSA whose population exceeds 200,000 shall be divided into two or more Urban MSSA Subdivisions.- Urban MSSA Subdivisions should be within a population range of 75,000 to 125,000, but may not be smaller than five square miles in area. If removing any census tract on the perimeter of the Urban MSSA Subdivision would cause the area to fall below five square miles in area, then the population of the Urban MSSA may exceed 125,000.- To the extent practicable, Urban MSSA Subdivisions should reflect recognized community and neighborhood boundaries and take into account such demographic information as income level and ethnicity. Rural Definitions:A rural MSSA is an MSSA adopted by the Commission, which has a population density of less than 250 persons per square mile, and which has no census defined place within the area with a population in excess of 50,000. Only the population that is located within the MSSA is counted in determining the population of the census defined place.A frontier MSSA is a rural MSSA adopted by the Commission which has a population density of less than 11 persons per square mile.Any MSSA which is not a rural or frontier MSSA is an urban MSSA.</note>
  <note displayLabel="Use limitation">The State of California, the California Health and Human Services Agency and the Office of Statewide Health Planning and Development make no representations or warranties regarding the accuracy of data or maps. The user will not seek to hold the State, the Agency or the Office liable under any circumstances for any damages with respect to any claim by the user or any third party on account of or arising from the use of data or maps. The user will cite the California Health and Human Services Agency and/or the Office as the original source of the data, but will clearly denote cases where the original data have been updated, modified, or in any way altered from the original condition. There are no restrictions on distribution of the data by users</note>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html" lang="eng">Medical care</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html" lang="eng">Health services accessibility</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html" lang="eng">Health service areas</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html" lang="eng">Medically underserved areas</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic lang="eng" valueURI="http://sws.geonames.org/3687919/" authority="geonames" authorityURI="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#">California</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <temporal encoding="w3cdtf">2010</temporal>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="health">Health</topic>
  </subject>
  <location>
    <url>http://purl.stanford.edu/ph637gq9746</url>
  </location>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Stanford</recordContentSource>
    <recordIdentifier>edu.stanford.purl:ph637gq9746</recordIdentifier>
    <recordOrigin>This record was translated from ISO 19139 to MODS v.3 using an xsl transformation.</recordOrigin>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
  </recordInfo>
  <extension displayLabel="geo">
    <rdf:RDF xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml/3.2/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://purl.stanford.edu/ph637gq9746">
        <dc:format>application/x-esri-shapefile; format=Shapefile</dc:format>
        <dc:type>Dataset#Polygon</dc:type>
        <gml:boundedBy>
          <gml:Envelope gml:srsName="EPSG:4326">
            <gml:lowerCorner>-124.409721 32.534157</gml:lowerCorner>
            <gml:upperCorner>-114.131212 42.009517</gml:upperCorner>
          </gml:Envelope>
        </gml:boundedBy>
      </rdf:Description>
    </rdf:RDF>
  </extension>
  <subject authority="EPSG" valueURI="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326" displayLabel="WGS84">
    <cartographics>
      <scale>Scale not given.</scale>
      <projection>EPSG::4326</projection>
      <coordinates>W 124°24ʹ35ʺ--W 114°7ʹ52ʺ/N 42°34ʺ--N 32°32ʹ3ʺ</coordinates>
    </cartographics>
  </subject>
  <note displayLabel="WGS84 Cartographics">This layer is presented in the WGS84 coordinate system for web display purposes. Downloadable data are provided in native coordinate system or projection.</note>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Healthcare Atlas of California</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <location>
      <url>https://purl.stanford.edu/qw778bk1665</url>
    </location>
    <typeOfResource collection="yes"/>
  </relatedItem>
  <accessCondition type="useAndReproduction">This item is in the public domain.  There are no restrictions on use.</accessCondition>
</mods>
