<?xml version="1.0"?>
<mods xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" version="3.4" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Hazardous Materials Sites - Facilities, San Mateo County Sea Level Rise Vulnerability Assessment Project, 2015</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <name type="corporate">
    <namePart>County of San Mateo Information Services Department</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <typeOfResource>cartographic</typeOfResource>
  <typeOfResource>software, multimedia</typeOfResource>
  <genre authority="lcgft" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/genreForms/gf2011026297">Geospatial data</genre>
  <genre authority="rdacontent" valueURI="http://rdvocab.info/termList/RDAContentType/1001">cartographic dataset</genre>
  <originInfo>
    <publisher>County of San Mateo Information Services Department</publisher>
    <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes">2019</dateIssued>
  </originInfo>
  <language>
    <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <physicalDescription>
    <form>Shapefile</form>
    <digitalOrigin>born digital</digitalOrigin>
  </physicalDescription>
  <subject>
    <cartographics>
      <scale>Scale not given.</scale>
      <projection>Custom projection</projection>
      <coordinates>(W 122&#xB0;23&#x2B9;44&#x2BA;--W 122&#xB0;12&#x2B9;44&#x2BA;/N 37&#xB0;41&#x2B9;--N 37&#xB0;29&#x2B9;10&#x2BA;)</coordinates>
    </cartographics>
  </subject>
  <abstract displayLabel="Abstract" lang="eng">This point shapefile represents facilities manufacuturing or handling hazardous materials in San Mateo County, California. These locations are primarily chemical and other utility faciltiies that are relevant to emergency response risk planning. Mapping associated with risk management plan facilties mapping, produced by US EPA. File was named "RMP_3_06.shp" prior to renaming. What is the Risk Management Program? When Congress passed the Clean Air Act Amendments of 1990, it required EPA to publish regulations and guidance for chemical accident prevention at facilities using extremely hazardous substances. The Risk Management Program Rule (RMP Rule) was written to implement Section 112(r) of these amendments. The rule, which built upon existing industry codes and standards, requires companies of all sizes that use certain flammable and toxic substances to develop a Risk Management Program, which includes a(n): " Hazard assessment that details the potential effects of an accidental release, an accident history of the last five years, and an evaluation of worst-case and alternative accidental releases; " Prevention program that includes safety precautions and maintenance, monitoring, and employee training measures; and " Emergency response program that spells out emergency health care, employee training measures and procedures for informing the public and response agencies (e.g the fire department) should an accident occur. By June 21, 1999, a summary of the facility's risk management program (known as a "Risk Management Plan" or "RMP") was to be submitted to EPA, which will make the information publicly available. The plans must be revised and resubmitted every five years. The Risk Management Program is about reducing chemical risk at the local level. This information helps local fire, police, and emergency response personnel (who must prepare for and respond to chemical accidents), and is useful to citizens in understanding the chemical hazards in communities. EPA anticipates that making the RMPs available to the public stimulates communication between industry and the public to improve accident prevention and emergency response practices at the local level. Who is Covered by the Risk Management Program? The List of Regulated Substances under section 112(r) of the Clean Air Act is found in 40 CFR Part 68 and lists the regulated substances, including their synonyms, and threshold quantities (in pounds) to help you assess if your process is subject to the RMP rule or the general duty clause. States who have taken delegation of the Clean Air Act, Section 112(r) program may have additional requirements for the Federally listed chemicals, and/or additional listed chemicals. For details, contact your implementing agency. What Software did EPA Develop to Assist the RMP Program? The Risk Management Program Rule, promulgated on June 21, 1996 under the Clean Air Act as Amended in 1990, stated: "The [Risk Management Plan] shall be submitted in method and format to a centra; point as specified by EPA prior to June 21, 1999." EPA adopted the recommendations of a subcommittee of the Clean Air Act Advisory Committee to require electronic submission of and access to Risk Management Plans. The final announcement of the "method and format" for RMP submission was published in the Federal Register in January 1999. Accordingly, EPA developed a suite of software applications to allow facilities to submit their RMPs in electronic format; to assist EPA in processing and managing the RMPs and create databases to allow government officials, industry, and the public to view RMP information; and to allow for searching and querying the databases. The applications include: RMP*Submit, a free personal computer software for facilities to use in submitting their Risk Management Plans. See the RMP*Submit page to download RMP*Submit and its user manual, to obtain the Electronic Waiver and paper RMP submission format, to find CBI forms, sample certification statement language, latitude and longitude instructions and Regional and State contact information. The RMP*Submit page also includes information on the RMP ASCII File Format Document, of use to those developing their own RMP submission systems. RMP*Info, a national database providing up to date information on RMPs submitted (this database had been on EPA's webpage but has been unavailable since shortly after 9/11/01). RMP*Review, a free program that can be used to review and analyze RMPs received by EPA. It has advanced query capabilities for users who want to analyze RMP data beyond the capabilities of RMP*Info (e.g. State Implementing Agencies, LEPCs, etc.). This layer is part of the San Mateo County Sea Level Rise Vulnerability Assessment Project.</abstract>
  <abstract displayLabel="Purpose" lang="eng"> These data are intended for researchers, students, and policy makers for reference and mapping purposes, and may be used for basic applications such as viewing, querying, and map output production.</abstract>
  <note displayLabel="Preferred citation" lang="eng">County of San Mateo Information Services Department. (2019). Hazardous Materials Sites - Facilities, San Mateo County Sea Level Rise Vulnerability Assessment Project, 2015. County of San Mateo Information Services Department. Available at: http://purl.stanford.edu/hr538ch5819.</note>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html" lang="eng">Hazardous waste sites</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic lang="eng" valueURI="http://sws.geonames.org/5392427/" authority="geonames" authorityURI="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#">San Mateo County (Calif.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <temporal encoding="w3cdtf">2015</temporal>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="environment">Environment</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="structure">Structure</topic>
  </subject>
  <location>
    <url>http://purl.stanford.edu/hr538ch5819</url>
  </location>
  <accessCondition type="useAndReproduction">These data are made available by San Mateo County as a public service. The data are for reference purposes only, and the County makes no representatives, warranties, or guarantees as to the accuracy of the data.</accessCondition>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Stanford</recordContentSource>
    <recordIdentifier>edu.stanford.purl:hr538ch5819</recordIdentifier>
    <recordOrigin>This record was translated from ISO 19139 to MODS v.3 using an xsl transformation.</recordOrigin>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
  </recordInfo>
  <extension displayLabel="geo">
    <rdf:RDF xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml/3.2/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://purl.stanford.edu/hr538ch5819">
        <dc:format>application/x-esri-shapefile; format=Shapefile</dc:format>
        <dc:type>Dataset#Point</dc:type>
        <gml:boundedBy>
          <gml:Envelope gml:srsName="EPSG:4326">
            <gml:lowerCorner>-122.395553 37.486045</gml:lowerCorner>
            <gml:upperCorner>-122.212143 37.683215</gml:upperCorner>
          </gml:Envelope>
        </gml:boundedBy>
        <dc:coverage rdf:resource="http://sws.geonames.org/5392427/" dc:language="eng" dc:title="San Mateo County (Calif.)"/>
      </rdf:Description>
    </rdf:RDF>
  </extension>
<subject authority="EPSG" valueURI="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326" displayLabel="WGS84"><cartographics><scale>Scale not given.</scale><projection>EPSG::4326</projection><coordinates>W 122&#xB0;23&#x2B9;44&#x2BA;--W 122&#xB0;12&#x2B9;44&#x2BA;/N 37&#xB0;41&#x2B9;--N 37&#xB0;29&#x2B9;10&#x2BA;</coordinates></cartographics></subject><note displayLabel="WGS84 Cartographics">This layer is presented in the WGS84 coordinate system for web display purposes. Downloadable data are provided in native coordinate system or projection.</note></mods>
