<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="3.7" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-7.xsd">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>California Geographic Names, 2000</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>California. Department of Fish and Game. Marine Resources Region</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">creator</roleTerm>
      </role>
    </name>
    <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Geological Survey (U.S.)</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">creator</roleTerm>
      </role>
    </name>
    <genre valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/genreForms/gf2011026297" authority="lcgft">Geospatial data</genre>
    <genre valueURI="http://rdvocab.info/termList/RDAContentType/1001" authority="rdacontent">cartographic dataset</genre>
    <typeOfResource>cartographic</typeOfResource>
    <typeOfResource>software, multimedia</typeOfResource>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form>Shapefile</form>
      <extent>3.447</extent>
      <digitalOrigin>born digital</digitalOrigin>
    </physicalDescription>
    <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <abstract lang="eng" displayLabel="Abstract">This point shapefile contains information on names, locations, and types of geographic features in California. The layer source is a custom state extract from the U.S. Geological Survey's (USGS) Geographic Names Information System (GNIS). GNIS contains geographic names for all known places, features, and areas in the United States that are identified by a proper name. In the layer, each feature is located by geographic coordinates and is referenced to the 1:24,000-scale USGS topographic map on which it is shown. This layer is part of a collection of data created by the California Department of Fish &amp;amp; Game.</abstract>
    <abstract lang="eng" displayLabel="Purpose">This layer is useful for locating landmarks, place names, and related locations and relating them to geographic coordinates.</abstract>
    <note lang="eng" displayLabel="Preferred citation">California Department of Fish and Game. Marine Resources Region. (2000). California Geographic Names, 2000. California Department of Fish and Game. Available at: http://purl.stanford.edu/dj677cf3811.</note>
    <note displayLabel="Supplemental information">Converted to California Teale Albers NAD83 by the California Department of Fish and Game -- BEGIN ORIGINAL METADATA - THIS INFORMATION MAY NOT BE CURRENT -- CALIFORNIA DEPARTMENT OF FISH AND GAME GIS METADATA California Geographic Names SHAPEFILE NAME: cagnis DATA PATH: METADATA FILE: cagnis.txt METADATA DATE: November 2000 METADATA UPDATE: January 2001 *** DRAFT *** METADATA PATH: * Processing metadata follow the metadata text * SHAPEFILE DESCRIPTION The cagnis shapefile contains information on names, locations, and types of geographic features in California. The source of this shapefile is a custom state extract from the U.S. Geological Survey's Geographic Names Information System (GNIS). GNIS contains geographic names for all known places, features, and areas in the United States that are identified by a proper name. In cagnis, each feature is located by geographic coordinates and is referenced to the 1:24,000-scale USGS topographic map on which it is shown. cagnis contains the 66 different features type defined by GNIS as of October 2000. Users are advised that these feature types are not exhaustive. For example, selecting the "school" type will not give you every California school, but it will furnish a large number of school locations. And there may be features in GNIS that are not yet represented on USGS map sheets. cagnis is useful for furnishing landmarks on plots and can also serve as a base data layer. The features types and names help to orient the viewer and give a sense of scale to the plot. Complete documentation on the GNIS is available at http://mapping.usgs.gov/www/gnis/ SPECIAL NOTE FOR CALIFORNIA DEPARTMENT OF FISH AND GAME USERS The USGS has determined that the locations and names of caves are sensitive information. The Department has public trust responsibilities to protect fish, wildlife, and plant resources and the habitats on which they depend, and has therefore maintained legacy GNIS cave references in cagnis. Users are urged to exercise discretion in the release of these data. VITAL STATISTICS Datum: NAD 27 Projection: Albers Units: Meters 1st Std. Parallel: 34 00 00 (34.0 degrees N) 2nd Std. Parallel: 40 30 00 (40.5 degrees N) Longitude of Origin: -120 00 00 (120.0 degrees W) Latitude of Origin: 00 00 00 (0.0 degrees) False Easting (X shift): 0 False Northing (Y shift): -4,000,000 Source: USGS Geographic Names Information System (GNIS) Source Media: GNIS Staff-prepared California file Source Projection: Geographic (latitude/longitude) Source Units: Degrees Source Scale: various Capture Method: data conversion Conversion Software: ArcView 3.2 and custom programming Data Structure: Vector ARC/INFO Coverage Type: Point ARC/INFO Precision: Single ARC/INFO Tolerances: Unknown Number of Features: 129095 Dataset Size: 60 MB, uncompressed shapefile set Data Updated: October 2000 for this California extract; USGS GNIS is subject to continuous update DATA DICTIONARY: DATAFILE NAME: cagnis.DBF Field Name,Type,Width,Decimal -- Description --------------------------------------------------------------------- SHAPE,SHAPEPOINT,6,0 -- ArcView point feature; one point per feature except where feature spans more than one quad (see SEQUENCE &gt; 1) ID,DECIMAL,11,0 -- USGS GNIS ID; value is primary key under USGS Oracle system GNIS_ID,DECIMAL,20,0 -- Legacy primary key retained by DFG; obsolete primary key per USGS; retained for referencing USEPA River Reach File 3 and other data. (aka "GIPSY-ID") FEAT_NAME,CHAR,66,0 -- Official name of feature FEAT_TYPE,CHAR,12,0 -- Type of feature LATDD,DECIMAL,20,5 -- Latitude of feature, decimal degrees LONDD,DECIMAL,20,5 -- Longitude of feature, decimal degrees CELLNAME,CHAR,27,0 -- Name of USGS 7.5' quad (cell) that point falls in ELEVAT_FT,DECIMAL,8,0 -- Elevation of feature, feet VARIANT,CHAR,254,0 -- Variant name(s) of feature (not official) SEQUENCE,DECIMAL,6,0 -- Coded as 1 for Primary coordinate of feature; coded as 2 and greater for each successive secondary coordinate DETAILED ITEM DESCRIPTIONS FEAT_TYPE: The feature type as classified by USGS. Valid TYPES are: arch cape gap mine slope area cave glacier other spring bar cem gut park stream basin channel harbor pillar summit bay church hosp plain swamp beach civil hospita ppl tank bench cliff island range trail bend crater lake rapids tunnel bldg dam lava reserve valley bridge falls levee reservo well buildin flat locale ridge woods canal forest militar school VARIANT_NM: other variant name by which feature may be known The following information is extracted from the Geographic Names Information System Data Users Guide 6, Department of the Interior, U.S Geological Survey, 1987. Users are advised to visit http://mapping.usgs.gov/www/gnis/ for the most current documentation. APPENDIX B.--Geographic Names Information System (GNIS) Feature Class Definitions The feature class terms and abbreviations currently consist of nine or fewer letters and were chosen for computer search and retrieval pur- poses. They do not necessarily represent terminology for the identifi- cation of all kinds of cultural and natural features. Although some of the terms may agree with dictionary definitions, they represent more generalized categories. Some commonly used generics are listed in paren- theses at the end of each entry to assist in understanding the range of cultural and natural entities represented by the term. Refer to the Reference Data Base to retrieve all generics thus far encountered in geographic names compilation. In most instances a plural form is listed as if it were singular; for example, archipelago or islands would be categorized as island. The terms and the definitions are as follows: airport - manmade facility maintained for the use of aircraft (airfield, airstrip, landing field, landing strip). arch - natural arch-like opening in a rock mass (bridge, natural bridge, sea arch). area - any one of several areally extensive natural features not included in other categories (badlands, barren, delta, fan, garden). arroyo - watercourse or channel through which water may occasionally flow (coulee, draw, gully, wash). bar - natural accumulation of sand, gravel, or alluvium forming an underwater or exposed embankment (ledge, reef, sandbar, shoal, spit). basin - natural depression or relatively low area enclosed by higher land (amphitheater, cirque, pit, sink). bay - indentation of a coastline or shoreline enclosing a part of a body of water; a body of water partly surrounded by land (arm, bight, cove, estuary, gulf, inlet, sound). beach - the sloping shore along a body of water that is washed by waves or tides and is usually covered by sand or gravel (coast, shore, strand). bench - area of relatively level land on the flank of an elevation such as a hill, ridge, or mountain where the slope of the land rises on one side and descends on the opposite side (level). bend - curve in the course of a stream and (or) the land within the curve; a curve in a linear body of water (bottom, loop, meander). bridge - manmade structure carrying a trail, road, or other trans- portation system across a body of water or depression (causeway, overpass, trestle). building - a manmade structure with walls and a roof for protection of people and (or) materials, but not including church, hospi- tal, or school. canal - manmade waterway used by watercraft or for drainage, irriga- tion, mining, or water power (ditch, lateral). cape - projection of land extending into a body of water (lea, neck, peninsula, point). cave - natural underground passageway or chamber, or a hollowed out cavity in the side of a cliff (cavern, grotto). cemetery - a place or area for burying the dead (burial, burying ground, grave, memorial garden). channel - linear deep part of a body of water through which the main volume of water flows and is frequently used as a route for watercraft (passage, reach, strait, thoroughfare, through- fare). church - building used for religious worship (chapel, mosque, syna- gogue, tabernacle, temple). civil - a political division formed for administrative purposes (borough, county, municipio, parish, town, township). cliff - very steep or vertical slope (bluff, crag, head, headland, nose, palisades, precipice, promontory, rim, rimrock). crater - circular-shaped depression at the summit of a volcanic cone or one on the surface of the land caused by the impact of a meteorite; a manmade depression caused by an explosion (caldera, lua). crossing - a place where two or more routes of transportation form a junction or intersection (overpass, underpass). dam - water barrier or embankment built across the course of a stream or into a body of water to control and (or) impound the flow of water (breakwater, dike, jetty). falls - perpendicular or very steep fall of water in the course of a stream (cascade, cataract, waterfall). flat - relative level area within a region of greater relief (clearing, glade, playa). forest - bounded area of woods, forest, or grassland under the ad- ministration of a political agency (see woods) (national forest, national grasslands, State forest). gap - low point or opening between hills or mountains or in a ridge or mountain range (col, notch, pass, saddle, water gap, wind gap) geyser - eruptive spring from which hot water and (or) steam and in some cases mud are periodically thrown. glacier - body or stream of ice moving outward and downslope from an area of accumulation; an area of relatively permanent snow or ice on the top or side of a mountain or mountainous area (icefield, ice patch, snow patch). gut - relatively small coastal waterway connecting larger bodies of water or other waterways (creek, inlet, slough). harbor - sheltered area of water where ships or other watercraft can anchor or dock (hono, port, roads, roadstead). hospital - building where the sick or injured may receive medical or surgical attention (infirmary). island - area of dry or relatively dry land surrounded by water or low wetland (archipelago, atoll, cay, hammock, hummock, isla, isle, key, moku, rock). isthmus - narrow section of land in a body of water connecting two larger land areas. lake - natural body of inland water (backwater, lac, lagoon, laguna, pond, pool, resaca, waterhole). lava - formations resulting from the consolidation of molten rock on the surface of the Earth (kepula, lava flow). levee - natural or manmade embankment flanking a stream (bank, berm). locale - place at which there is or was human activity; it does not include populated places, mines, and dams (battlefield, crossroad, camp, farm, ghost town, landing, railroad siding, ranch, ruins, site, station, windmill). mine - place or area from which commercial minerals are or were removed from the Earth; not including oilfield (pit, quarry, shaft). oilfield - area where petroleum is or was removed from the Earth. other - category for miscellaneous named manmade, entities that cannot readily be placed in the other feature classes listed here. park - place or area set aside for recreation or preservation of a cultural or natural resource and under some form of govern- ment administration; not including National or State forests- or Reserves (national historical landmark, national park, State park, wilderness area). pillar - vertical, standing, often spire-shaped, natural rock forma- tion (chimney, monument, pinnacle, pohaku, rock tower). plain - a region of general uniform slope, comparatively level and of considerable extent (grassland, highland, kula, plateau, upland). ppl - (populated place) place or area with clustered or scattered buildings and a permanent human population (city, settlement, town, village). range - chain of hills or mountains, a somewhat linear, complex mountainous or hilly area (cordillera, sierra). rapids - fast-flowing section of a stream, often shallow and with exposed rock or boulders (riffle, ripple). reserve - a tract of land set aside for a specific use (does not include forests, civil divisions, parks). reservoir - artificially impounded body of water (lake, tank). ridge - elevation with a narrow, elongated crest which can be part of a hill or mountain (crest, cuesta, escarpment, hogback, lae, rim, spur). school - building or group of buildings used as an institution for study, teaching, and learning (academy, college, high school, university). sea - large body of salt water (gulf, ocean). slope - a gently inclined part of the Earth's surface (grade, pitch). spring - place where underground water flows naturally to the surface of the Earth (seep). stream - linear body of water flowing on the Earth's surface (ana- branch, awawa, bayou, branch, brook, creek, distributary, fork, kill, pup, rio, river, run, slough). summit - prominent elevation rising above the surrounding level of the Earth's surface; does not include pillars, ridges, or ranges (ahu, berg, bald, butte, cerro, colina, cone, cumbre, dome, head, hill, horn, knob, knoll, mauna, mesa, mesita, mound, mount, mountain, peak, puu, rock, Sugarloaf, table, volcano). swamp - poorly drained wetland, fresh or saltwater, wooded or grassy, possibly covered with open water (bog, cienega, marais, marsh, pocosin). trail - route for passage from one point to another; does not include roads or highways (jeep trail, path, ski trail). tower - a manmade structure, higher than its diameter, generally used for observation, storage, or electronic transmission. tunnel - linear underground passageway open at both ends. valley - linear depression in the Earth's surface that generally slopes from one end to the other (barranca, canyon, chasm, cove, draw, glen, gorge, gulch, gulf, hollow, ravine). well - manmade shaft or hole in the Earth's surface used to obtain fluid or gaseous materials. woods - small area covered with a dense growth of trees; does not include an area of trees under the administration of a political agency (see forest). APPENDIX C.--Parenthetical Descriptors used with Names The following terms have been used on USGS topographic maps and other sources to provide additional information or clarity about the name or the feature to which the name refers. Abandoned Active Mine Alkali Archaeological Site BLM - refers to Bureau of Land Management Campground Cemetery Diabase Dike Dry Spring Flowing Foot Bridge Ghost Town Historic Historical Historical Monument Historical Ruins Historic Site Inactive Mine Jeep Trail Mud Natural Arch Oil Field Old Channel Old Stage Station Oxbow P.O. - refers to Post Office Pack Trail Placer - refers to mining activities Polluted Spring Post Office Private Rock Formation Ruins Salt Lake Secondary Name - refers to alternate or a prior name; for example: Lake Katy (Old River Lake) Siding Site Station Submerged Rock Sulphur Spring USDA - refers to U.S. Department of Agriculture USFS - refers to U.S. Forest Service USGS - refers to U.S. Geological Survey 1941 - refers to year of occurrence DATA QUALITY ASSESSMENT The following are subjective comments regarding this data. Feature completeness is good, as is attribute completeness. The feature and attribute accuracy is also good. USGS DATA CONTACT Name: Mark Brooks Phone: 703-648-4547 E-mail: mbrooks@usgs.gov DFG PROCESSING CONTACT Name: Isaac Oshima Phone: 916-323-1635 E-mail: ioshima@dfg.ca.gov DFG METADATA CONTACT Name: Paul Veisze Phone: 916-323-1667 E-mail: pveisze@dfg.ca.gov Data first Version: March 5, 1996 Data last edited: November 9, 2000 Metadata edited: January 4, 2001 REVISION DETAILS November 9, 2000 GNIS Update ============================ The files used to update GNIS (03/05/1996) were obtained by Paul Veisze (pveisze@dfg.ca.gov) from a request to the USGS/GNIS Staff, transmitted by Mark Brooks (mbrooks@usgs.gov) on 10/17/2000. Isaac Oshima (ioshima@dfg.ca.gov) prepared the shapefile cagnis, updating a similar DFG dataset of March 5, 1996. The following metadata text was supplied with the GNIS extract files of October 2000: == begin USGS-supplied metadata == Ca_list1.txt - File contains all primary data Column 1 - Feature ID Column 2 - Gipsy ID Column 3 - Feature Name Column 4 - Feature Type Column 5 - State FIPS Numeric Code Column 6 - County FIPS Numeric Code Column 7 - County Name Column 8 - Primary Latitude (decimal) Column 9 - Primary Longitude (decimal) Column 10 - Primary Latitude (dms) Column 11 - Primary Longitude (dms) Column 12 - Cell Name (7.5' USGS Quadrangle) Column 13 - Source Latitude (decimal) Column 14 - Source Longitude (decimal) Column 15 - Source Latitude (dms) Column 16 - Source Longitude (dms) Column 17 - Elevation Column 18 - Total Population (Bureau of Census 1994/incorporated place only) Column 19 - Federal Status (BGN) Ca_list1_var.txt - File contains all variant names and biblio codes Column 1 - Feature ID Column 2 - Variant Name Column 3 - Biblio Code Ca_list2_coord.txt - File contains all secondary coordinates for features that have more than one coordinate Column 1 - Feature ID Column 2 - Sequence Number (starts with sequence number 2) Column 3 - Cell Name (7.5' USGS Quadrangle) Column 4 - Secondary Latitude (decimal) Column 5 - Secondary Longitude (decimal) Column 6 - Secondary Latitude (dms) Column 7 - Secondary Longitude (dms) == end USGS-supplied metadata == REVISION STATISTICS The previous DFG compilation of a California extract of GNIS contained 86,139 unique features. Note that GNIS may contain multiple points for a single unique feature such as a river (consisting of primary coordinate and one or more secondary coordinates). The count figures presented here reflect only one point feature instance. This 11/09/2000 revision contains 104,133 single unique features; an increase of 17,994. The individual feature type counts are listed in comma-delimited format below. "Feat_type","oldcount","newcount","chgcount" airport,996,990,-6 arch,18,20,2 area,281,289,8 arroyo,0,2,2 bar,277,281,4 basin,503,498,-5 bay,382,426,44 beach,241,282,41 bench,30,31,1 bend,100,99,-1 bridge,146,157,11 building,2006,4065,2059 canal,2284,2297,13 canyon,0,1,1 cape,627,662,35 cave,83,0,-83 cemetery,687,804,117 channel,97,104,7 church,1642,7377,5735 civil,642,666,24 cliff,186,187,1 crater,24,24,0 crossing,86,96,10 dam,1554,1469,-85 falls,163,174,11 flat,2676,2706,30 forest,44,41,-3 gap,670,670,0 geyser,1,2,1 glacier,21,21,0 gut,217,217,0 harbor,86,103,17 hospital,510,824,314 island,505,529,24 isthmus,1,1,0 lake,2688,2641,-47 lava,15,15,0 levee,17,23,6 locale,10634,13489,2855 military,44,53,9 mine,2920,3069,149 oilfield,123,128,5 other,209,134,-75 park,3967,6728,2761 pillar,300,305,5 plain,27,26,-1 po,403,1046,643 ppl,6104,7477,1373 range,310,302,-8 rapids,10,10,0 reserve,80,80,0 reservoir,1421,1404,-17 ridge,1750,1755,5 school,8704,11068,2364 sea,1,2,1 slope,43,43,0 spring,3056,3080,24 stream,9955,9893,-62 summit,5535,5600,65 swamp,94,98,4 tower,969,972,3 trail,808,1182,374 tunnel,122,127,5 valley,7639,7613,-26 well,232,237,5 woods,173,197,24 REVISION MODIFICATIONS DFG performed minor field modifications in the current revision. USGS GNIS Staff provided some DFG-requested fields in the delivered .txt files: Ca_list1.txt - File contains all primary data Column 1 - Feature ID (named ID in November 2000 processing of CA data) Column 2 - Gipsy ID (named GNIS_ID by DFG in cagnis) Column 12 - Cell Name (7.5' USGS Quadrangle Map Name) Ca_list2_coord.txt - File contains all secondary coordinates for features that have more than one coordinate, e.g. for streams, the mouth is the primary coordinate. Secondary coordinates (and additional shapepoints) are posted for every quad the stream flows through. Column 2 - Sequence Number (starts with sequence number 2) "Feature ID" is the current GNIS name of its primary key, but is named "ID" in this DFG rendition of the California extract (as it was in previous DFG versions). Values of "ID" in the cagnis are current as primary keys, except for FEATURE_TYPE = "cave". New versions of GNIS do not include the feature type "cave", due to federal legislation mandating their treatment as sensitive data. DFG is maintaining legacy GNIS cave data as part of its public trust responsibilities. DFG generated a special set of IDs for caves: The ID for caves is "999" + the legacy GNIS_ID. "Gipsy ID" is a legacy, obsolete GNIS primary key. DFG is maintaining the legacy values under the field name "GNIS_ID" for references to features coded in USEPA's River Reach File under the "Primary Name Code" (PNMCD) for hydrographic features (rivers and streams). DFG implements "GNIS_ID" now as a numeric instead of a character field. The Cell Name field is the USGS 7.5' Quadname and is a new field. The elevat_ft field is now numeric. The Sequence Number field is new and contains the sequence number for those features that have more than one coordinate. REVISION EXCLUSIONS The old and new versions of the California extract of GNIS contain more fields than are represented in the DFG processed GIS dataset. DFG dropped fields where these were either very sparsely populated or could be derived from other GIS layers such as county or state FIPS codes. There were many spurious data points outside of California. Most of the points that were reasonably off-shore were kept. Those north, south and east into Oregon, Arizona, and Nevada respectively were clipped using a 1 kilometer buffer around the California border. ==end of file cagnis.txt -- END ORIGINAL METADATA --</note>
    <note displayLabel="WGS84 Cartographics">This layer is presented in the WGS84 coordinate system for web display purposes. Downloadable data are provided in native coordinate system or projection.</note>
    <subject authority="lcsh" lang="eng">
      <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html">Landmarks</topic>
    </subject>
    <subject authority="geonames" lang="eng">
      <geographic authority="geonames" authorityURI="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#" valueURI="http://sws.geonames.org/3687919/">California</geographic>
    </subject>
    <subject>
      <temporal encoding="w3cdtf">2000</temporal>
    </subject>
    <subject authority="ISO19115TopicCategory">
      <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="society">Society</topic>
    </subject>
    <subject authority="ISO19115TopicCategory">
      <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode">Geoscientific Information</topic>
    </subject>
    <subject authority="ISO19115TopicCategory">
      <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="location">Location</topic>
    </subject>
    <subject authority="ISO19115TopicCategory">
      <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="economy">Economy</topic>
    </subject>
    <subject authority="ISO19115TopicCategory">
      <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="environment">Environment</topic>
    </subject>
    <subject authority="ISO19115TopicCategory">
      <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="structure">Structure</topic>
    </subject>
    <subject>
      <cartographics>
        <scale>Scale not given.</scale>
        <projection>Custom projection</projection>
        <coordinates>W 124°35ʹ1ʺ--W 113°30ʹ25ʺ/N 42°4ʹ2ʺ--N 32°25ʹ34ʺ</coordinates>
        <coordinates>W 124°28ʹ56ʺ--W 114°8ʹ16ʺ/N 42°37ʺ--N 32°32ʹ10ʺ</coordinates>
      </cartographics>
    </subject>
    <subject displayLabel="WGS84" authority="EPSG" valueURI="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
      <cartographics>
        <projection>EPSG::4326</projection>
      </cartographics>
    </subject>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes">2000</dateIssued>
      <place>
        <placeTerm type="text">Monterey, CA, US</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <publisher>California. Department of Fish and Game. Marine Resources Region</publisher>
    </originInfo>
    <location>
      <url usage="primary display">https://purl.stanford.edu/dj677cf3811</url>
    </location>
    <recordInfo>
      <languageOfCataloging>
        <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
      <recordContentSource>Stanford</recordContentSource>
      <recordOrigin>This record was translated from ISO 19139 to MODS v.3 using an xsl transformation.</recordOrigin>
      <recordIdentifier>edu.stanford.purl:dj677cf3811</recordIdentifier>
    </recordInfo>
    <extension displayLabel="geo">
      <rdf:RDF xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml/3.2/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
        <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://purl.stanford.edu/dj677cf3811">
          <dc:format>application/x-esri-shapefile; format=Shapefile</dc:format>
          <dc:type>Dataset#Point</dc:type>
          <gml:boundedBy>
            <gml:Envelope gml:srsName="EPSG:4326">
              <gml:lowerCorner>-124.482278 32.536167</gml:lowerCorner>
              <gml:upperCorner>-114.13772 42.01041</gml:upperCorner>
            </gml:Envelope>
          </gml:boundedBy>
        </rdf:Description>
      </rdf:RDF>
    </extension>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>California Department of Fish and Wildlife GIS Maps &amp; Data</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <location>
        <url>https://purl.stanford.edu/fb282pw3043</url>
      </location>
      <typeOfResource collection="yes"/>
    </relatedItem>
    <accessCondition type="useAndReproduction">This item is in the public domain.  There are no restrictions on use.</accessCondition>
    <accessCondition type="copyright">This work is in the Public Domain, meaning that it is not subject to copyright.</accessCondition>
  </mods>
