<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" version="3.4" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>2-Meter Bathymetric Digital Elevation Model: Southern Section of North Monterey Bay, California, 2009</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <name type="corporate">
    <namePart>Western Coastal and Marine Geology Program (Geological Survey)</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name type="corporate">
    <namePart>Seafloor Mapping Lab</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <typeOfResource>cartographic</typeOfResource>
  <typeOfResource>software, multimedia</typeOfResource>
  <genre authority="lcgft" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/genreForms/gf2011026297">Geospatial data</genre>
  <genre authority="rdacontent" valueURI="http://rdvocab.info/termList/RDAContentType/1001">cartographic dataset</genre>
  <originInfo>
    <publisher>Seafloor Mapping Lab</publisher>
    <place>
      <placeTerm type="text">Seaside, California, US</placeTerm>
    </place>
    <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes">2010</dateIssued>
    <dateValid encoding="w3cdtf">2009</dateValid>
  </originInfo>
  <language>
    <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <physicalDescription>
    <form>Raster Dataset</form>
    <digitalOrigin>born digital</digitalOrigin>
  </physicalDescription>
  <subject>
    <cartographics>
      <scale>Scale not given.</scale>
      <projection>EPSG::26910</projection>
      <coordinates>(W 122°6ʹ12ʺ--W 121°47ʹ11ʺ/N 37°2ʹ34ʺ--N 36°47ʹ36ʺ)</coordinates>
    </cartographics>
  </subject>
  <abstract displayLabel="Abstract" lang="eng">This raster dataset is a 2-meter digital elevation model containing multibeam bathymetry data for the southern section of North Monterey Bay, California collected from a USGS Western Coastal &amp;amp; Marine Geology survey of the Monterey Bay area from Año Nuevo to Moss Landing. These data were acquired between August 13- September 3, 2009 (field activity S-7-09-MB), from Point Año Nuevo south to Table Rock, as well as a block west of Soquel Canyon; and between October 12 - December 16, 2009 (field activity S-10-09-MB), surveying between Table Rock and Moss Landing. Habitat analyses and final products derived from multibeam bathymetry data were handled by the Seafloor Mapping Lab at CSUMB. This layer was created as part of the California Seafloor Mapping Project.</abstract>
  <abstract displayLabel="Purpose" lang="eng">Marine data offered here represent the efforts of a comprehensive state waters mapping program for California launched by the California State Coastal Conservancy, Ocean Protection Council, Department of Fish and Game, and the NOAA National Marine Sanctuary Program. The ultimate goal is the creation of a high-resolution 1:24,000 scale geologic and habitat base map series covering all of California's 14,500 km2 state waters out to the 3 mile limit, and support of the state's Marine Life Protection Act Initiative (MLPA) goal to create a statewide network of Marine Protected Areas (MPAs). This statewide project requires, involves and leverages expertise from industry, resource management agencies and academia. The tiered mapping campaign involves the use of state-of-the-art sonar, LIDAR (aerial laser) and video seafloor mapping technologies; computer aided classification and visualization; expert geologic and habitat interpretations codified into strip maps spanning California's land/sea boundary; and the creation of an online, publicly accessible data repository for the dissemination of all mapping products.</abstract>
  <note displayLabel="Preferred citation" lang="eng">USGS Western Coastal and Marine Geology Program and Seafloor Mapping Lab. (2010). 2-Meter Bathymetric Digital Elevation Model: Southern Section of North Monterey Bay, California, 2009. Seafloor Mapping Lab Available at: http://purl.stanford.edu/qg355tf9327</note>
  <note displayLabel="Supplemental information">Raw sonar data were processed with SEA Swath Processor (version 3.05.18.04) before being cleaned and prepared for CARIS with sxpegn (build 151) by David Finlayson (USGS). Data were then imported to CARIS HIPS and SIPS (version 7.0.1.0 Service Pack 1). Within CARIS, field sheets were created to tile the data into smaller work areas, and survey lines were trimmed to optimize overlap, water column noise was removed, and data were gridded to 2m resolution using a swath angle BASE surface. Data were then exported from CARIS as ascii XYZ files and imported to ARCGIS where they were combined into a single grid. data were then exported as a single continuous ASCII grid.

Bathymetry products are presented according to standard California State Mapping Project specifications, including depth-dependent resolutions of 2m for data from the 0-85m depth range, 5m for 80-250m depth range, and 10m for depths of 230-1500m. A comprehensive 5m data set was produced for the total survey coverage only if per block data exceeded 85m depth and 5m resolution products were included. </note>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html" lang="eng">Continental margins</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html" lang="eng">Bathymetric maps</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html" lang="eng">Digital elevation models</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic lang="eng" valueURI="http://sws.geonames.org/5374363/" authority="geonames" authorityURI="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#">Monterey Bay (Calif.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <temporal encoding="w3cdtf">2009</temporal>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="elevation">Elevation</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="imageryBaseMapsEarthCover">Imagery and Base Maps</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="inlandWaters">Inland Waters</topic>
  </subject>
  <location>
    <url>http://purl.stanford.edu/qg355tf9327</url>
  </location>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Stanford</recordContentSource>
    <recordIdentifier>edu.stanford.purl:qg355tf9327</recordIdentifier>
    <recordOrigin>This record was translated from ISO 19139 to MODS v.3 using an xsl transformation.</recordOrigin>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
  </recordInfo>
  <extension displayLabel="geo">
    <rdf:RDF xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml/3.2/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://purl.stanford.edu/qg355tf9327">
        <dc:format>image/tiff; format=ArcGRID</dc:format>
        <dc:type>Dataset#Raster</dc:type>
        <gml:boundedBy>
          <gml:Envelope gml:srsName="EPSG:26910">
            <gml:lowerCorner>-122.10328 36.793432</gml:lowerCorner>
            <gml:upperCorner>-121.786366 37.042812</gml:upperCorner>
          </gml:Envelope>
        </gml:boundedBy>
        <dc:coverage rdf:resource="http://sws.geonames.org/5374363/about.rdf" dc:language="eng" dc:title="Monterey Bay (Calif.)"/>
      </rdf:Description>
    </rdf:RDF>
  </extension>
</mods>
