<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" version="3.4" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Bulletin 118 - Groundwater Basins and Subbasins, California, 2003</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <name type="corporate">
    <namePart>California. Department of Water Resources</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <typeOfResource>cartographic</typeOfResource>
  <typeOfResource>software, multimedia</typeOfResource>
  <genre authority="lcgft" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/genreForms/gf2011026297">Geospatial data</genre>
  <genre authority="rdacontent" valueURI="http://rdvocab.info/termList/RDAContentType/1001">cartographic dataset</genre>
  <originInfo>
    <publisher>California. Department of Water Resources</publisher>
    <place>
      <placeTerm type="text">Sacramento, California, US</placeTerm>
    </place>
    <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes">2015</dateIssued>
  </originInfo>
  <language>
    <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <physicalDescription>
    <form>Shapefile</form>
    <extent>4.857</extent>
    <digitalOrigin>born digital</digitalOrigin>
  </physicalDescription>
  <subject>
    <cartographics>
      <scale>Scale not given.</scale>
      <projection>Custom projection</projection>
      <coordinates>(W 124°27ʹ36ʺ--W 113°36ʹ5ʺ/N 42°1ʹ9ʺ--N 32°25ʹ41ʺ)</coordinates>
    </cartographics>
  </subject>
  <abstract displayLabel="Abstract" lang="eng">The polygon shapefile contains the boundaries of 515 groundwater basins and subbasins as defined by the California Department of Water Resources (Bulletin 118, 2003). Groundwater basins are represented as polygon features and designated on the basis of geological and hydrological conditions - usually the occurrence of alluvial or unconsolidated deposits. When practical, large basins are also subdivided by political boundaries, as in the Central Valley. Basins are named and numbered per the convention of the Department of Water Resources. The associated data are considered DWR enterprise GIS data, which meet all appropriate requirements of the DWR GIS Spatial Data Standards. DWR makes no warranties or guarantees, either expressed or implied, as to the completeness, accuracy or correctness of the data, nor accepts or assumes any liability arising from or for any incorrect, incomplete or misleading subject data.</abstract>
  <abstract displayLabel="Purpose" lang="eng">Bulletin 118 defines the recognized groundwater basins and subbasins throughout the State of California. The Bulletin 118 document provides information on these basins/subbasins and the nature and extent of groundwater occurrence and management within the State. The Bulletin 118 dataset makes the geographic locations and extent of the 515 basins/subbasins publically available, for use in external mapping/GIS applications.</abstract>
  <note displayLabel="Attribute accuracy report" lang="eng">Horizontal positional accuracy was established by professional judgement. According to Bill Brewster, 100% of the linework is better than 10 mile accuracy. Some places are better than 10 mile accuracy.</note>
  <note displayLabel="Preferred citation" lang="eng">California Department of Water Resources. (2015). Bulletin 118 - Groundwater Basins and Subbasins, California, 2003. California Department of Water Resources. Available at: http://purl.stanford.edu/kt110sd4399.</note>
  <note displayLabel="Supplemental information">Origination of Data - The basin boundaries for the groundwater basin map were primarily defined using geologic contacts and hydrogeologic divides. Specifically, the identification of the groundwater basins was initially based on the presence and areal extent of unconsolidated alluvial soils identified on 1:250,000 scale geologic maps provided by the California Department of Conservation, Division of Mines and Geology. The identified groundwater basin areas were then further evaluated through review of relevant geologic and hydrogeologic reports, well completion reports, court-determined adjudicated basin boundaries, and contact with local agencies to refine the basin boundaries. Date - The latest version of DWR’s Bulletin 118 document is dated October, 2003, and is available at: http://www.water.ca.gov/groundwater/bulletin118/update2003.cfm The current dataset was updated at the time the latest Bulletin 118 document was produced, and is based on geological maps and other information available at that time. There have been minor corrections to the dataset since that time, as described in the data lineage. Additional Contacts - Contacts Statewide Data Steward: Brett Wyckoff Senior Engineering Geologist California Department of Water Resources Division of Integrated Regional Water Management (916) 651-9283 Brett.Wyckoff@water.ca.gov Region Office Data Sub-stewards: Northern Region Office Jonathan Mulder Engineering Geologist (530) 528-7423 Jonathan.Mulder@water.ca.gov North-Central Region Office Bill Brewster Engineering Geologist (916) 376-9622 Bill.Brewster@water.ca.gov South-Central Region Office Mike McKenzie Engineering Geologist (559) 230-3308 Charles.McKenzie@water.ca.gov Southern Region Office Matt Zimmerman Engineering Geologist (818) 500-1645 Matthew.Zimmerman@water.ca.gov Update Frequency: Changes to the dataset are made on an infrequent and irregular basis. Minor changes are occasionally made and will be documented in the metadata. Substantial changes, such as the extent of a basin boundary, must be completed as part of a public process, where the changes are proposed and public review and comment are welcomed before any changes are finalized.</note>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html" lang="eng">Groundwater</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html" lang="eng">Basins (Geology)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html" lang="eng">Aquifers</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html" lang="eng">Hydrogeology</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic lang="eng" valueURI="http://sws.geonames.org/3687919/" authority="geonames" authorityURI="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#">California</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <temporal encoding="w3cdtf">2003</temporal>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode">Geoscientific Information</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="boundaries">Boundaries</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="inlandWaters">Inland Waters</topic>
  </subject>
  <location>
    <url>http://purl.stanford.edu/kt110sd4399</url>
  </location>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Stanford</recordContentSource>
    <recordIdentifier>edu.stanford.purl:kt110sd4399</recordIdentifier>
    <recordOrigin>This record was translated from ISO 19139 to MODS v.3 using an xsl transformation.</recordOrigin>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
  </recordInfo>
  <extension displayLabel="geo">
    <rdf:RDF xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml/3.2/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://purl.stanford.edu/kt110sd4399">
        <dc:format>application/x-esri-shapefile; format=Shapefile</dc:format>
        <dc:type>Dataset#Polygon</dc:type>
        <gml:boundedBy>
          <gml:Envelope gml:srsName="EPSG:4326">
            <gml:lowerCorner>-124.358559 32.534028</gml:lowerCorner>
            <gml:upperCorner>-114.225818 42.003788</gml:upperCorner>
          </gml:Envelope>
        </gml:boundedBy>
      </rdf:Description>
    </rdf:RDF>
  </extension>
  <subject authority="EPSG" valueURI="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326" displayLabel="WGS84">
    <cartographics>
      <scale>Scale not given.</scale>
      <projection>EPSG::4326</projection>
      <coordinates>W 124°21ʹ31ʺ--W 114°13ʹ33ʺ/N 42°14ʺ--N 32°32ʹ3ʺ</coordinates>
    </cartographics>
  </subject>
  <note displayLabel="WGS84 Cartographics">This layer is presented in the WGS84 coordinate system for web display purposes. Downloadable data are provided in native coordinate system or projection.</note>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Groundwater Information Center, California: GIS Maps and Data</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <location>
      <url>https://purl.stanford.edu/cz385jp1958</url>
    </location>
    <typeOfResource collection="yes"/>
  </relatedItem>
  <accessCondition type="useAndReproduction">This item is in the public domain.  There are no restrictions on use.</accessCondition>
</mods>
