<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" version="3.4" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>2000 Census Blocks, Demographic Data: Russian River Basin, California</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <name type="corporate">
    <namePart>Circuit Rider Productions</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <typeOfResource>cartographic</typeOfResource>
  <typeOfResource>software, multimedia</typeOfResource>
  <genre authority="lcgft" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/genreForms/gf2011026297">Geospatial data</genre>
  <genre authority="rdacontent" valueURI="http://rdvocab.info/termList/RDAContentType/1001">cartographic dataset</genre>
  <originInfo>
    <publisher>Circuit Rider Productions</publisher>
    <place>
      <placeTerm type="text">Windsor, California, US</placeTerm>
    </place>
    <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes">2002</dateIssued>
    <dateValid encoding="w3cdtf">2000</dateValid>
  </originInfo>
  <language>
    <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <physicalDescription>
    <form>Shapefile</form>
    <extent>3.915</extent>
    <digitalOrigin>born digital</digitalOrigin>
  </physicalDescription>
  <subject>
    <cartographics>
      <scale>Scale not given.</scale>
      <projection>EPSG::26910</projection>
      <coordinates>(W 123°26ʹ53ʺ--W 122°23ʹ32ʺ/N 39°25ʹ14ʺ--N 38°15ʹ18ʺ)</coordinates>
    </cartographics>
  </subject>
  <abstract displayLabel="Abstract" lang="eng">This polygon shapefile contains the portion of the 2000 census blocks, summary file 1 (SF1) demographic data coverage that is within the watershed boundaries of the Russian River basin in California. Census TIGER are registered trademarks of the Bureau of the Census. The Redistricting Census 2000 TIGER/Line files are an extract of selected geographic and cartographic information from the Census TIGER data base. The geographic coverage for a single TIGER/Line file is a county or statistical equivalent entity, with the coverage area based on January 1, 2000 legal boundaries. A complete set of Redistricting Census 2000 TIGER/Line files includes all counties and statistically equivalent entities in the United States and Puerto Rico. The Redistricting Census 2000 TIGER/Line files will not include files for the Island Areas. The Census TIGER data base represents a seamless national file with no overlaps or gaps between parts. However, each county-based TIGER/Line file is designed to stand alone as an independent data set or the files can be combined to cover the whole Nation. The Redistricting Census 2000 TIGER/Line files consist of line segments representing physical features and governmental and statistical boundaries. The Redistricting Census 2000 TIGER/Line files do NOT contain the ZIP Code Tabulation Areas (ZCTAs) and the address ranges are of approximately the same vintage as those appearing in the 1999 TIGER/Line files. That is, the Census Bureau is producing the Redistricting Census 2000 TIGER/Line files in advance of the computer processing that will ensure that the address ranges in the TIGER/Line files agree with the final Master Address File (MAF) used for tabulating Census 2000. The files contain information distributed over a series of record types for the spatial objects of a county. There are 17 record types, including the basic data record, the shape coordinate points, and geographic codes that can be used with appropriate software to prepare maps. Other geographic information contained in the files includes attributes such as feature identifiers/census feature class codes (CFCC) used to differentiate feature types, address ranges and ZIP Codes, codes for legal and statistical entities, latitude/longitude coordinates of linear and point features, landmark point features, area landmarks, key geographic features, and area boundaries. The Redistricting Census 2000 TIGER/Line data dictionary contains a complete list of all the fields in the 17 record types.</abstract>
  <abstract displayLabel="Purpose" lang="eng">This layer can be used for watershed analysis and planning in the Russian River region of California. In order for others to use the information in the Census TIGER data base in a geographic information system (GIS) or for other geographic applications, the Census Bureau releases to the public extracts of the data base in the form of TIGER/Line files. Various versions of the TIGER/Line files have been released; previous versions include the 1990 Census TIGER/Line files, the 1992 TIGER/Line files, the 1994 TIGER/Line files, the 1995 TIGER/Line files, the 1997 TIGER/Line files, the 1998 TIGER/Line files, and the 1999 TIGER/Line files. The Redistricting Census 2000 TIGER/Line files were originally produced to support the Census 2000 Redistricting Data Program.</abstract>
  <note displayLabel="Preferred citation" lang="eng">Circuit Rider Productions and National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (2002). 2000 Census Blocks, Demographic Data: Russian River Basin, California. Circuit Rider Productions. Available at: http://purl.stanford.edu/yt423xd2317</note>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html" lang="eng">Census districts</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic lang="eng" valueURI="http://sws.geonames.org/5397100/" authority="geonames" authorityURI="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#">Sonoma County (Calif.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic lang="eng" valueURI="http://sws.geonames.org/5372163/" authority="geonames" authorityURI="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#">Mendocino County (Calif.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic lang="eng" valueURI="http://sws.geonames.org/5389382/" authority="geonames" authorityURI="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#">Russian River Watershed (Calif.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <temporal encoding="w3cdtf">2000</temporal>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="boundaries">Boundaries</topic>
  </subject>
  <location>
    <url>http://purl.stanford.edu/yt423xd2317</url>
  </location>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Stanford</recordContentSource>
    <recordIdentifier>edu.stanford.purl:yt423xd2317</recordIdentifier>
    <recordOrigin>This record was translated from ISO 19139 to MODS v.3 using an xsl transformation.</recordOrigin>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
  </recordInfo>
  <extension displayLabel="geo">
    <rdf:RDF xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml/3.2/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://purl.stanford.edu/yt423xd2317">
        <dc:format>application/x-esri-shapefile; format=Shapefile</dc:format>
        <dc:type>Dataset#Polygon</dc:type>
        <gml:boundedBy>
          <gml:Envelope gml:srsName="EPSG:26910">
            <gml:lowerCorner>-123.448034 38.255123</gml:lowerCorner>
            <gml:upperCorner>-122.392345 39.420574</gml:upperCorner>
          </gml:Envelope>
        </gml:boundedBy>
        <dc:coverage rdf:resource="http://sws.geonames.org/5397100/about.rdf" dc:language="eng" dc:title="Sonoma County (Calif.)"/>
        <dc:coverage rdf:resource="http://sws.geonames.org/5372163/about.rdf" dc:language="eng" dc:title="Mendocino County (Calif.)"/>
        <dc:coverage rdf:resource="http://sws.geonames.org/5389382/about.rdf" dc:language="eng" dc:title="Russian River Watershed (Calif.)"/>
      </rdf:Description>
    </rdf:RDF>
  </extension>
</mods>
