<?xml version="1.0"?>
<mods xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" version="3.4" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>LandScan 2010 Global Population Database</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <name type="corporate">
    <namePart>Oak Ridge National Laboratory</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <typeOfResource>cartographic</typeOfResource>
  <typeOfResource>software, multimedia</typeOfResource>
  <genre authority="lcgft" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/genreForms/gf2011026297">Geospatial data</genre>
  <genre authority="rdacontent" valueURI="http://rdvocab.info/termList/RDAContentType/1001">cartographic dataset</genre>
  <originInfo>
    <publisher>Oak Ridge National Laboratory</publisher>
    <place>
      <placeTerm type="text">Oak Ridge, TENNESSEE, US</placeTerm>
    </place>
    <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes">2011</dateIssued>
    <edition>2010</edition>
  </originInfo>
  <language>
    <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <physicalDescription>
    <form>Raster Dataset</form>
    <digitalOrigin>born digital</digitalOrigin>
  </physicalDescription>
  <subject>
    <cartographics>
      <scale>Scale not given.</scale>
      <projection>Custom projection</projection>
      <coordinates>(W 180&#xB0;--E 180&#xB0;/N 84&#xB0;--S 90&#xB0;)</coordinates>
    </cartographics>
  </subject>
  <abstract displayLabel="Abstract" lang="eng">The LandScan 2010 global population data set is a worldwide population database compiled on a 30" X 30" latitude/longitude grid. Census counts (at sub-national level) were apportioned to each grid cell based on likelihood coefficients, which are based on proximity to roads, slope, land cover, nighttime lights, and other data sets. LandScan has been developed as part of the Oak Ridge National Laboratory (ORNL) Global Population Project for estimating ambient populations at risk. The LandScan files are available via the internet in ESRI grid format by continent and for the world. At approximately 1 km resolution (30" X 30"), There is also a "Layer" file (lspop2000.lyr) for ArcGIS. LandScan is the finest resolution global population distribution data available and represents an ambient population (average over 24 hours). This dataset is part of the LandScan 2000 Global Population Database (2000-2010).</abstract>
  <abstract displayLabel="Purpose" lang="eng">Developed for the U. S. Department of Defense. "The values of the cells are integer population counts representing an average, or ambient, population distribution. An ambient population integrates diurnal movements and collective travel habits into a single measure (Dobson et al. 2000). Since natural or man made emergencies may occur at any time of the day, the goal of the LandScan model is to develop a population distribution surface in totality, not just the locations of where people sleep. Because of this ambient nature, care should be taken with direct comparisons of LandScan data with other population distribution surfaces." --from the Oak Ridge National Laboratory LandScan Web site, Sept. 12, 2013.</abstract>
  <note displayLabel="Preferred citation" lang="eng">Oak Ridge National Laboratory. (2011). LandScan 2010 Global Population Database. Oak Ridge National Laboratory, UT-Battelle, LLC. Available at: https://purl.stanford.edu/by855gg8349
</note>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html" lang="eng">Administrative and political divisions</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html" lang="eng">Population</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic lang="eng" valueURI="http://sws.geonames.org/6295630/" authority="geonames" authorityURI="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#">Earth (Planet)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <temporal encoding="w3cdtf">2010</temporal>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="imageryBaseMapsEarthCover">Imagery and Base Maps</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="society">Society</topic>
  </subject>
  <location>
    <url>https://purl.stanford.edu/by855gg8349</url>
  </location>
  <accessCondition type="useAndReproduction">Licensee agrees to use its best efforts to provide UT-Batelle information on an annual basis about its utilization of the Dataset including a list of publications or presentations wherein the Dataset is used. If this dataset is used in a publication or presentation, please notify the distributor so that information can be shared with the dataset originator. Licensee agrees to apply the following notice to all tangible forms of products, including graphs or pictorial presentations, which are produced or generated utilizing the licensed LandScan 2000 High Resolution Global Population Dataset, or to the packaging thereof if direct application to products is not feasible: This product was made utilizing the LandScan 2000&#x2122; High Resolution global Population Data Set copyrighted by UT-Battelle, LLC, operator of Oak Ridge National Laboratory under Contract No. DE-AC05-00OR22725 with the United States Department of Energy. The United States Government has certain rights in this Data Set. Neither UT-BATTELLE, LLC NOR THE UNITED STATES DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY, NOR ANY OF THEIR EMPLOYEES, MAKES ANY WARRANTY, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, OR ASSUMES ANY LEGAL LIABILITY OR RESPONSIBILITY FOR THE ACCURACY, COMPLETENESS, OR USEFULNESS OF THE DATA SET. If the product is a single image or something similar where space does not permit use of the entire notice shown above, Licensee shall apply the following credit line to such images or similar products: Source: LandScan 2000, ORNL, UT-Battelle, LLC
</accessCondition>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Stanford</recordContentSource>
    <recordIdentifier>edu.stanford.purl:by855gg8349</recordIdentifier>
    <recordOrigin>This record was translated from ISO 19139 to MODS v.3 using an xsl transformation.</recordOrigin>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
  </recordInfo>
  <extension displayLabel="geo">
    <rdf:RDF xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml/3.2/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about="https://purl.stanford.edu/by855gg8349">
        <dc:format>application/x-ogc-aig; format=ArcGRID</dc:format>
        <dc:type>Dataset#Raster</dc:type>
        <gml:boundedBy>
          <gml:Envelope gml:srsName="EPSG:4326">
            <gml:lowerCorner>-180.0 -90.0</gml:lowerCorner>
            <gml:upperCorner>180.0 84.0</gml:upperCorner>
          </gml:Envelope>
        </gml:boundedBy>
        <dc:coverage rdf:resource="http://sws.geonames.org/6295630/" dc:language="eng" dc:title="Earth (Planet)"/>
      </rdf:Description>
    </rdf:RDF>
  </extension>
<subject authority="EPSG" valueURI="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326" displayLabel="WGS84"><cartographics><scale>Scale not given.</scale><projection>EPSG::4326</projection><coordinates>W 180&#xB0;--E 180&#xB0;/N 84&#xB0;--S 90&#xB0;</coordinates></cartographics></subject><note displayLabel="WGS84 Cartographics">This layer is presented in the WGS84 coordinate system for web display purposes. Downloadable data are provided in native coordinate system or projection.</note></mods>
