<?xml version="1.0"?>
<mods xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" version="3.4" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Maritime Limits: California, 2005</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <name type="corporate">
    <namePart>United States. Office of Coast Survey</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name type="corporate">
    <namePart>United States. Department of Commerce</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name type="corporate">
    <namePart>United States. National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name type="corporate">
    <namePart>United States. National Ocean Service</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <typeOfResource>cartographic</typeOfResource>
  <typeOfResource>software, multimedia</typeOfResource>
  <genre authority="lcgft" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/genreForms/gf2011026297">Geospatial data</genre>
  <genre authority="rdacontent" valueURI="http://rdvocab.info/termList/RDAContentType/1001">cartographic dataset</genre>
  <originInfo>
    <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes">2005</dateIssued>
    <dateValid encoding="w3cdtf">2005</dateValid>
  </originInfo>
  <language>
    <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <physicalDescription>
    <form>Shapefile</form>
    <extent>0.394</extent>
    <digitalOrigin>born digital</digitalOrigin>
  </physicalDescription>
  <subject>
    <cartographics>
      <scale>Scale not given.</scale>
      <projection>Custom projection</projection>
      <coordinates>(W 124&#xB0;38&#x2B9;2&#x2BA;--W 116&#xB0;48&#x2B9;21&#x2BA;/N 42&#xB0;4&#x2B9;27&#x2BA;--N 32&#xB0;29&#x2B9;29&#x2BA;)</coordinates>
    </cartographics>
  </subject>
  <abstract displayLabel="Abstract" lang="eng">This line shapefile represents the maritime limits of California. NOAA's Office of Coast Survey (OCS) is responsible for generating the 3 Nautical Mile Line, Territorial Sea, Contiguous Zone, and Exclusive Economic Zone (EEZ). Traditionally, these maritime limits have been generated by hand from the low water line depicted on paper and United States nautical charts. Upon final approval by the United States Baseline Committee, these legally-binding maritime limits are applied to the next edition of nautical charts produced by the Marine Chart Division of OCS. Due to new cartographic production processes and the availability of digital products such as Electronic Navigational Charts (ENCs), OCS has developed improved techniques for generating more accurate, digital maritime limits.</abstract>
  <abstract displayLabel="Purpose" lang="eng">This coverage can be used as a source for depiction of maritime limits on National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration's (NOAA) paper nautical charts and electronic navigational charts. The maritime limits were constructed from baseline points that represent the most seaward, drying features at mean lower low water on NOAA's largest scale, latest edition, paper nautical charts of the area. These digital boundaries do NOT represent the legal depiction of maritime limits.</abstract>
  <note displayLabel="Preferred citation" lang="eng">California Department of Fish and Wildlife Marine Resources Region. (2005). Maritime Limits: California, 2005. California Department of Fish and Wildlife. Marine Resources Region. Available at: http://purl.stanford.edu/gy157tv4692.</note>
  <note displayLabel="Supplemental information">Marine Region GIS lab updates: As the California / Oregon border was not delineated for calculation or boundary purposes, the file was modified to reflect California's boundary. The boundary line was not altered, just clipped out to the extent of California's borders. Also, only the 3 nautical mile line is included in this version. The territorial sea, contiguous zone, and EEZ have been omitted from this dataset for the purposes of including only California's state waters out to 3 nautical miles. == Original text document that accompanied the data set: "maritimelimits_teale_nad83.txt" Preliminary Metadata Processing Steps: 1. Download available California maritime limits from http://nauticalcharts.noaa.gov/csdl/mbound.htm Posted 2005-09-15, accessed 2005-12-05 2. Merge Oregon and Washington maritime limits (Westington, 2005-12, personal communication); ArcView 3.x, Geoprocessing Extension 3. Project to California Teale Albers, NAD 83 (California Shapefile Projector; 12/13/2003) 4. Rename output "maritimelimits_teale_nad83.shp" Processing Contact: Paul Veisze, pveisze@dfg.ca.gov Supplementary Information (source: http://nauticalcharts.noaa.gov/csdl/mbound.htm): For NOAA/National Ocean Service Nautical Charts Maritime boundaries for the United States are determined from the official U.S. baseline, recognized as the low-water line along the coast as marked on the official U.S. nautical charts in accordance with the articles of the Law of the Sea. The Office of Coast Survey is responsible for determining and depicting the Three Nautical Mile Line, Territorial Sea, Contiguous Zone, and Exclusive Economic Zone on NOAA's nautical charts. Download Digital Maritime Limits The following links contain zipped shapefiles of the Three Nautical Mile Line, Territorial Sea (12 naut. mi.), and Contiguous Zone (24 naut. mi.) as represented on NOAA's nautical charts. For more information about each dataset, metadata is also provided. If you do not have software to view these shapefiles, ESRI has a free viewer to download at http://www.esri.com/software/arcexplorer/download.html. This site will be updated frequently with new digital boundary information. Note: To download the current EEZ data, please go to http://nauticalcharts.noaa.gov/csdl/eez.htm. Location Metadata? Date Posted Hawaiian Islands Yes 2004-02-23 Northwestern Hawaiian Islands Yes 2003-08-27 Puerto Rico and U.S Virgin Is. Yes 2004-03-01 Maine Yes 2004-06-15 New Hampshire and Massachusetts Yes 2004-06-29 Rhode Island and New York Yes 2004-07-08 New Jersey, Delaware, and Maryland Yes 2004-07-19 Virginia, North Carolina, and South Carolina Yes 2004-10-07 Florida and Alabama Yes 2005-06-09 Mississippi and Louisiana Yes 2005-03-03 California Yes 2005-09-15 Descriptions of Maritime Limits Three Nautical Mile Line-- The Three Nautical Mile Line, previously identified as the outer limit of the territorial sea, is retained on NOAA's nautical charts as it continues to depict the jurisdictional limit of other laws. The 9-nautical mile Natural Resource Boundary off the Gulf coast of Florida, Texas, and Puerto Rico, and the Three Nautical Mile Line elsewhere remain in most cases the inner limit of Federal fisheries jurisdiction and the outer limit of the jurisdiction of the states. The territorial sea was extended from three to twelve nautical miles by Presidential Proclamation No. 5928 on December 27, 1988. Territorial Sea-- The territorial sea is delimited either from base points on the land mass (normally at the low-water line along the coast) or from baselines connecting such points in accordance with international law. The coastal state enjoys sovereignty and jurisdiction over the territorial sea subject to the right of innocent passage for foreign vessels. The maximum breadth of the territorial sea allowed under international law as reflected in the LOS Convention is twelve nautical miles. Contiguous Zone-- Presidential Proclamation No. 7219 on August 2, 1999 extended the Contiguous Zone from its prior limit of 12 nautical miles from the baseline to 24 nautical miles. Under international law, a contiguous zone is an area contiguous to a nation's territorial sea and in which the nation may exercise the control necessary to prevent infringement of its customs, fiscal, sanitation, or immigration laws and regulations within its territory or territorial sea. It may also exercise the control necessary to punish infringement of the above laws and regulations committed within its territory or territorial sea. This Proclamation has limited immediate effect, because the contiguous zone is defined in various statutes and regulations in such a manner as to mean 12 nautical miles. As an example, the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (FWPCA) and the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act (CERCLA) both limit the contiguous zone to 12 nautical miles. Revised Thursday September 15 2005by OCS Webmaster == begin original metadata Identification_Information: Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: Department of Commerce (DOC), National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 20050426 (Southern California) 20050628 (Northern California) Title: Approved Maritime Limits for California, USA Edition: v. 1.0 Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: vector digital data Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, Maryland Publisher: NOAA's National Ocean Service, Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Online_Linkage: http://nauticalcharts.noaa.gov/csdl/mbound.htm Description: Abstract: NOAA's Office of Coast Survey (OCS) is responsible for generating the 3 Nautical Mile Line, Territorial Sea, Contiguous Zone, and Exclusive Economic Zone (EEZ). Traditionally, these maritime limits have been generated by hand from the low water line depicted on paper, U.S. nautical charts. Upon final approval by the U.S. Baseline Committee, these legally-binding maritime limits are applied to the next edition of nautical charts produced by the Marine Chart Division of OCS. Due to new cartographic production processes and the availability of digital products such as Electronic Navigational Charts (ENCs), OCS has developed improved techniques for generating more accurate, digital maritime limits. Through the use of Geographic Information Systems (GIS) software such as CARIS' LOTS and ESRI's ArcGIS, the latest vector representations of these limits will be available to NOAA cartographers and the public. To create digital limits, the charted low water line is captured digitally and used as input to CARIS' LOTS: Limits and Boundaries software for the designation of a baseline. Once the limits are created, they are exported to a shapefile file using CARIS' Import SHP utility. These polyline shapefiles are contained within a zipped file. Purpose: This dataset is to be used as the source for the depiction of maritime limits on NOAA's paper nautical charts and electronic navigational charts. The maritime limits were constructed from baseline points that represent the most seaward, drying features at mean lower low water on NOAA's largest scale, latest edition, paper nautical charts of the area. These digital boundaries do NOT represent the legal depiction of the maritime limits. Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 2005 Currentness_Reference: publication date Status: Progress: Complete Maintenance_and_Update_Frequency: Continually Spatial_Domain: Bounding_Coordinates: West_Bounding_Coordinate: -125.33450 East_Bounding_Coordinate: -116.80250 North_Bounding_Coordinate: 42.84983 South_Bounding_Coordinate: 32.38333 Keywords: Theme: Theme_Keyword_Thesaurus: None Theme_Keyword: GIS Theme_Keyword: Boundary Theme_Keyword: Baseline Theme_Keyword: Limits Theme_Keyword: 3 Nautical Mile Line Theme_Keyword: Maritime Theme_Keyword: Law of the Sea Theme_Keyword: Territorial Sea Theme_Keyword: Contiguous Zone Theme: Theme_Keyword_Thesaurus: ISO 19115 Topic Category Theme_Keyword: boundaries Theme_Keyword: planningCadastre Place: Place_Keyword_Thesaurus: None Place_Keyword: California Place_Keyword: Pacific Ocean Place_Keyword: Santa Cruz Island Place_Keyword: Santa Catalina Island Place_Keyword: Santa Barbara Island Place_Keyword: San Clemente Island Place_Keyword: Pacific Coast Place_Keyword: Port of San Pedro Place_Keyword: San Diego Harbor Place_Keyword: San Nicolas Island Place_Keyword: San Miguel Island Place_Keyword: Santa Rosa Island Place_Keyword: Santa Cruz Island Place_Keyword: Anacapa Island Place_Keyword: Richardson Rock Place_Keyword: Wilson Rock Place_Keyword: Begg Rock Place_Keyword: Santa Monica Bay Place_Keyword: San Luis Obispo Bay Place_Keyword: Morro Bay Place_Keyword: Estero Bay Place_Keyword: Monterey Bay Place_Keyword: Half Moon Bay Place_Keyword: San Francisco Bay Place_Keyword: Bodega-Tomales Bay Place_Keyword: Humboldt Bay Place_Keyword: Drakes Bay Place_Keyword: St George Reef Place_Keyword: Reading Rock Access_Constraints: NONE Use_Constraints: NOT FOR LEGAL USE Point_of_Contact: Contact_Information: Contact_Organization_Primary: Contact_Organization: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Contact_Position: Chief Geographer Contact_Address: Address_Type: mailing and physical address Address: 1315 East-West Highway N/CSx5 City: Silver Spring State_or_Province: Maryland Postal_Code: 20910 Country: USA Contact_Voice_Telephone: (301) 713-2780 x127 Contact_Facsimile_Telephone: 301-713-4501 Contact_Electronic_Mail_Address: Meredith.Westington@noaa.gov Hours_of_Service: Monday - Friday, 0900 EST - 1700 EST Native_Data_Set_Environment: CARIS' Law of the Sea: Limits and Boundaries v. 4.04, Win XP Data_Quality_Information: Attribute_Accuracy: Attribute_Accuracy_Report: In CARIS LOTS, two working mapping files was used for the project area of California. The map projections were set to Mercator with a 0.001 meter X/Y resolution for Northern California. The map projections were set to Mercator with a .0002 meter X/Y resolution for Southern California. The two working mapping files were later blended together with a map projection set to Mercator with a .001 X/Y resolution. The scaling latitude used for the CARIS maps were determined by finding the midpoints between the northeast and southwest bounding coordinates of each project area. The baseline points were derived from the largest scale charts. As NOAA's raster nautical charts were brought into the CARIS environment, the CARIS map was reprojected on the fly to match the chart's projection. To aid in the baseline point designation process, NOAA utilized the Extracted Vector Shoreline product. This product contains the vector low water line extracted from source binary raster files which are compiled to create the paper nautical chart. The Extracted Vector Shoreline was adjusted to achieve a 1 to 1 correspondence between it and the raster nautical chart. In some instances, the Extracted Vector Shoreline did not provide full coverage; therefore, heads-up digitizing in the CARIS environment was necessary. Once the baseline was determined, limit lines were projected through a method called envelope of arcs. Each limit line was attributed after export from LOTS to shpfile format. The attributes are Limit, Location, State, Approved Date, Source Scale Range, Begining Chart Year, Ending Chart Year, and Chart Datum. No added tests were conducted. Logical_Consistency_Report: The data, which reflects the largest scale nautical charts of the area, are believed to be logically consistent. Completeness_Report: The maritime limits are complete for California. The limits may be updated at a later date if the charted depiction of the farthest seaward low-water mark changes. These limits were created for internal purposes only to improve the accuracy of the charted maritime limits. These limits are not designed for legal purposes. For a legal depiction of the limits, please see NOAA's paper or raster nautical charts. Positional_Accuracy: Horizontal_Positional_Accuracy: Horizontal_Positional_Accuracy_Report: No specific test was performed on the dataset. The data is a reflection of the largest scale raster nautical charts of the area. The number of decimal places used in the output format does not imply an accuracy level higher than the source chart documents. Vertical_Positional_Accuracy: Vertical_Positional_Accuracy_Report: The maritime limits are projected from a designated baseline. Points representing the baseline are referenced from the farthest seaward low-water mark as depicted on the largest scale, raster nautical charts. No specific test was used to determine the vertical accuracy of the points. Lineage: Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1996-2005 Title: Maptech's BSB-format raster nautical charts: 18600, 18602_1, 18603_1, 18603_2, 18605, 18620_1, 18620_2, 18620_3, 18622, 18623, 18626_1, 18626_2, 18626_3, 18628_1, 18628_2, 18640, 18643_1, 18643_2, 18645_1, 18645_2, 18647, 18649, 18652_1, 18680, 18682, 18685_1, 18686, 18700, 18703_1, 18703_2, 18704, 18720, 18721, 18724_1, 18724_2, 18725_1, 18725_2, 18725_3, 18725_4, 18727_1, 18727_2, 18728, 18729_1, 18729_2, 18744_1, 18744_2, 18744_3, 18746_1, 18746_2, 18749_1, 18749_2, 18751, 18754, 18755, 18756, 18757_1, 18757_2, 18757_3, 18757_4, 18758, 18762, 18763_1, 18763_2, 18764, 18765_1, 18765_2, 18772, 18773_1, 18774_1 Edition: latest edition Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: raster digital data Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, Maryland Publisher: NOAA's National Ocean Service, Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Online_Linkage: Nautical Charts: http://nauticalcharts.noaa.gov/staff/charts.htm Source_Scale_Denominator: 10,000 Type_of_Source_Media: raster nautical chart Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Range_of_Dates/Times: Beginning_Date: 1996 Ending_Date: 2005 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: BSB Source_Contribution: The maritime limits are created from normal baseline points. Points representing the baseline are referenced from the farthest seaward low-water mark as depicted on the largest scale, paper nautical charts. NOAA's raster nautical charts were used as backdrops in the CARIS map. As these charts were brought into the CARIS environment, the CARIS map was reprojected on the fly to match the chart's projection. The latest edition charts were used as referenced in the citation information section above. The dates of these latest editions were current as of 2005. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 2001-2005 Title: Vector Shoreline of NOAA's raster nautical charts: 18600, 18602_1, 18603_1, 18603_2, 18605, 18620_1, 18620_2, 18620_3, 18622, 18623, 18626_1, 18626_2, 18626_3, 18628_1, 18628_2, 18640, 18643_1, 18643_2, 18645_1, 18645_2, 18647, 18649, 18652_1, 18680, 18682, 18685_1, 18686, 18700, 18703_1, 18703_2, 18704, 18720, 18721, 18724_1, 18724_2, 18725_1, 18725_2, 18725_3, 18725_4, 18727_1, 18727_2, 18728, 18729_1, 18729_2, 18744_1, 18744_2, 18744_3, 18746_1, 18746_2, 18749_1, 18749_2, 18751, 18754, 18755, 18756, 18757_1, 18757_2, 18757_3, 18757_4, 18758, 18762, 18763_1, 18763_2, 18764, 18765_1, 18765_2, 18772, 18773_1, 18774_1 Edition: latest edition Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: vector digital data Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, Maryland Publisher: NOAA's National Ocean Service, Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Online_Linkage: http://nauticalcharts.noaa.gov/csdl/ctp/cm_vs.htm Source_Scale_Denominator: 10,000 Type_of_Source_Media: online, vector Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Range_of_Dates/Times: Beginning_Date: 1996 Ending_Date: 2005 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: VECSHORE Source_Contribution: CARIS LOTS has a tool called the "Envelope of Arcs," which requires a vector low water line input in order to create the limits and determine contributing baseline points. NOAA's Extracted Vector Shoreline (EVS) was used when available to make the job of boundary delimitation more efficient. The EVS' mean lower low water and mean high water lines were merged using Safe's Feature Manipulation Engine (FME) to a single low water line. Modification of the EVS occurred in the CARIS environment to achieve a 1 to 1 relationship between the raster nautical chart and the extracted low water line. In some cases, either not enough information was provided in the EVS or there was no EVS available for a particular chart. In these cases, the low water line was delineated through heads-up digitizing in the CARIS environment. The resulting vector low water line was used as input to the "Envelope of Arcs" tool. This vector low water line corresponds to the latest edition raster nautical chart as referenced in the citation information section above. The dates of these latest editions were current as of 2005. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1970 Title: H09107-Southern Coast of California, Vicinity of La Jolla Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 10,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1970 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of an asterisk symbol at Bird Rock on NOAA's nautical chart is a drying feature at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1978 Title: H09752-California, Santa Barbara Channel Punta Gorda to Santa Barbara Point Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: National Ocean Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 20,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1978 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of an asterisk symbol near Santa Barbara on NOAA's nautical chart is a drying feature at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1971 Title: H09250-Gulf of Santa Catalina, Carlsbad Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: National Ocean Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 10,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1971 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of an asterisk symbol near Oceanside on NOAA's nautical chart is a drying feature at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1974 Title: H09468-Gulf of Santa Catalina, Dana Point to Laguna Beach Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: National Ocean Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 10,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1974 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of four asterisk symbols near Three Arch Bay, Aliso Creek, and Laguna Beach Oceanside on NOAA's nautical chart are drying features at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1974 Title: H09469-Gulf of Santa Catalina, Laguna Beach to Newport Beach Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: National Ocean Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 10,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1974 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of four asterisk symbols off Reef Point, Abalone Point, and Corona del Mar on NOAA's nautical chart are drying features at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1933 Title: H05498-Seacliff to Sand Point, Santa Barbara Channel Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 10,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1933 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of an asterisk symbol near Carpinteria Creek on NOAA's nautical chart is a drying feature at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1975 Title: H09499-Santa Catalina Island, Goat Harbor to West End Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: National Ocean Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 20,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1975 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of four asterisk symbols at Rippers Cove, Black Point, and West End on NOAA's nautical chart are drying features at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1934 Title: H05555-Santa Catalina Island, Western Part Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 20,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1934 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of an asterisk symbol at Whale Rock on NOAA's nautical chart is a drying feature at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1933 Title: H05445-Anacapa Island, Santa Barbara Channel Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 20,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1933 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of an asterisk symbol at Arch Rock on NOAA's nautical chart is a drying feature at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1935 Title: H05683-San Miguel Island, Santa Barbara Channel Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 20,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1935 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of three asterisk symbols at Point Bennett, Adams Cove, and Cardwell Point on NOAA's nautical chart are drying features at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1935 Title: H05696-Bechers Bay and Vicinity, Santa Rosa Island Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 10,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1935 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of five asterisk symbols at Carrington Point and Beacon Reef on NOAA's nautical chart are drying features at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1935 Title: H05699-Valley Anchorage to Kinton Point, Santa Cruz Island South Side Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 20,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1935 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of two asterisk symbols west of Blue Banks Anchorage and at Yellow Bluff on NOAA's nautical chart are drying features at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1934-1935 Title: H05695-Platts Harbor to Kinton Point, Santa Cruz Island Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 20,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1935 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of two asterisk symbols at Fraser Point and west of Profile Point on NOAA's nautical chart are drying features at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1934 Title: H05658-Santa Catalina Island, Eastern Part Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 20,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1934 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of five asterisk symbols north of China Point, at Salta Verde Point, northwest of Binnacle Rock, and at Church Rock on NOAA's nautical chart are drying features at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1934-1935 Title: H05701-Bee Rk and Rodes Reef, Santa Rosa Island, West End Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 20,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1934-1935 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of an asterisk symbol at Sandy Point on NOAA's nautical chart is a drying feature at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1934 Title: H05660-Santa Cruz Island, Eastern Part Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 20,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1934 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of three asterisk symbols at Sandstone Point and Middle Anchorage on NOAA's nautical chart are drying features at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1933 Title: H05390-Kellers Shelter to Point Dume, Santa Monica Bay Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 10,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1933 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of an asterisk symbol at Dume Cove on NOAA's nautical chart is a drying feature at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1933-1934 Title: H05741-Point Pedernales to Santa Inez River, Southern California Coast Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 10,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1933-1934 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of two asterisk symbols at Destroyer Rock and near Honda on NOAA's nautical chart are drying features at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1973-1974 Title: H09376-San Clemente Island, West Side of San Clemente Island Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: National Ocean Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 20,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1973-1974 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of seven asterisk symbols on the westside of San Clemente Island, at Seal Cove, Mail Point, and Lost Point on NOAA's nautical chart are drying features at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1973-1974 Title: H09377-San Clemente Island, South End of San Clemente Island Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: National Ocean Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 20,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1973-1974 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of six asterisk symbols at China Point, Pyramid Head, and north of Mosquito Cove on NOAA's nautical chart are drying features at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1975 Title: H09498-Santa Catalina Island, Seal Rocks and Goat Harbor Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: National Ocean Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 20,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1975 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of an asterisk symbol at Long Point on NOAA's nautical chart is a drying feature at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1975 Title: H09558-Santa Monica Bay, Pt. Vicente to Redondo Beach Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: National Ocean Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 10,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1975 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of two asterisk symbols at Point Vicente and Lunada Bay on NOAA's nautical chart are drying features at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1976 Title: H09598-Santa Monica Bay, Vicinity of Malibu Beach Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: National Ocean Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 10,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1976 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of two asterisk symbols at Mailbu Point and near Las Flores on NOAA's nautical chart are drying features at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1976-1977 Title: H09599-Santa Monica Bay, Vicinity of Point Dume Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: National Ocean Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 10,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1976-1977 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of eight asterisk symbols at Paradise Cove, Point Dume, near Trancas Canyon, and Los Alisos Canyon on NOAA's nautical chart are drying features at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1976 Title: H09600-San Pedro Channel, East of Pt. Mugu and West of Pt. Dume Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: National Ocean Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 10,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1976 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of three asterisk symbols near Los Alisos Canyon and Arroyo Sequit on NOAA's nautical chart are drying features at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1976 Title: H09667-Santa Barbara Channel, Point Mugu Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: National Ocean Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 20,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1976 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of two asterisk symbols at Point Mugu on NOAA's nautical chart are drying features at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1984 Title: H10164-Santa Barbara Channel, Santa Barbara to Naples Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: National Ocean Service Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 20,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1984 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of five asterisk symbols near Santa Barbara on NOAA's nautical chart are drying features at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1984 Title: H10165-Santa Barbara Channel, Coal Oil Point and Vicinity Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: National Ocean Service Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 10,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1984 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of an asterisk symbol at Goleta Point on NOAA's nautical chart is a drying feature at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1996 Title: H10706-Santa Barbara Channel, Approaches to Gaviota Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: National Ocean Service Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 10,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1996 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of four asterisk symbols near Gaviota on NOAA's nautical chart are drying features at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1985 Title: H10171-Santa Barbara Channel, Gaviota to Point Conception Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: National Ocean Service Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 20,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1985 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of three asterisk symbols near Sacafe and Gato on NOAA's nautical chart are drying features at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1984 Title: H10161-Santa Barbara Channel, Naples to Gaviota Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: National Ocean Service Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 20,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1984 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of four asterisk symbols near Canada del Refugio and Tajiguas Creek on NOAA's nautical chart are drying features at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1996 Title: H10708-Santa Barbara Channel, Approaches to Ellwood Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: National Ocean Service Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 10,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1996 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of two asterisk symbols at Goleta Point and near Naples on NOAA's nautical chart are drying features at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1928 Title: H04862-Point St George/St George Reef Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: US Coast and Geodetic Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 20,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1928 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of an asterisk symbol at Great Break on NOAA's nautical chart is a drying feature at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1929 Title: H04965-Klamath River to near Crescent City Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: US Coast and Geodetic Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 20,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1929 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of an asterisk symbol at Requa on NOAA's nautical chart is a drying feature at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1929 Title: H04966-Mussel Point to Klamath River and in the vicinity of Redding Rk L.H. Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: US Coast and Geodetic Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 20,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1929 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of an asterisk symbol near Johnson Creek on NOAA's nautical chart is a drying feature at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 2005 Title: United States Coast Pilot 7-Pacific Coast: California, Oregon, Washington, Hawaii, and Pacific Islands Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: free text Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Greenbelt, MD Publisher: Fedearl Aviation Administration (FAA), National Aeronautical Charting Office Type_of_Source_Media: book Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 2005 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: CP Source_Contribution: The coast pilot was referenced to ensure that the depiction of Reading Rock, which is obscured by a light symbol on NOAA's nautical chart is in fact a drying feature at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1929 Title: H04997-Trinidad Head to Rocky Pt Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: US Coast and Geodetic Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 10,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1929 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of an asterisk symbol at Green Rock on NOAA's nautical chart is a drying feature at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1937-1938 Title: H06420-False Cape Rock to Centerville Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: US Coast and Geodetic Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 10,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1937-1938 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of an asterisk symbol near False Cape Rock on NOAA's nautical chart is a drying feature at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1937 Title: H06406-Blunts Reef &amp; Vicinity off Cape Mendocino Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: US Coast and Geodetic Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denominator: 20,000 Type_of_Source_Media: hydrographic survey Source_Time_Period_of_Content: Time_Period_Information: Single_Date/Time: Calendar_Date: 1937 Source_Currentness_Reference: publication date Source_Citation_Abbreviation: HYDSUR Source_Contribution: The hydrographic survey was referenced to ensure that the depiction of two asterisk symbols near Blunts Reef on NOAA's nautical chart are drying features at mean lower low water. Source_Information: Source_Citation: Citation_Information: Originator: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS) Publication_Date: 1936 Title: H06164-Cooksie Creek to Mattole River Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form: smoothsheet Publication_Information: Publication_Place: Silver Spring, MD Publisher: US Coast and Geodetic Survey Other_Citation_Details: This hydrographic survey was conducted at the vertical reference of mean lower low water. Source_Scale_Denomi</note>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html" lang="eng">Coasts</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html" lang="eng">Territorial waters</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html" lang="eng">Contiguous zones (Law of the sea)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html" lang="eng">Economic zones (Law of the sea)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html" lang="eng">Maritime boundaries</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects.html" lang="eng">Cartography</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic lang="eng" valueURI="http://sws.geonames.org/3687919/" authority="geonames" authorityURI="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#">California</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic lang="eng" valueURI="http://sws.geonames.org/8411083/" authority="geonames" authorityURI="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#">Pacific Ocean</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <temporal encoding="w3cdtf">2005</temporal>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="boundaries">Boundaries</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="oceans">Oceans</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="economy">Economy</topic>
  </subject>
  <location>
    <url>http://purl.stanford.edu/gy157tv4692</url>
  </location>
  <accessCondition type="useAndReproduction">No restrictions on access or use. Please cite the authors when possible.</accessCondition>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Stanford</recordContentSource>
    <recordIdentifier>edu.stanford.purl:gy157tv4692</recordIdentifier>
    <recordOrigin>This record was translated from ISO 19139 to MODS v.3 using an xsl transformation.</recordOrigin>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
  </recordInfo>
  <extension displayLabel="geo">
    <rdf:RDF xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml/3.2/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://purl.stanford.edu/gy157tv4692">
        <dc:format>application/x-esri-shapefile; format=Shapefile</dc:format>
        <dc:type>Dataset#LineString</dc:type>
        <gml:boundedBy>
          <gml:Envelope gml:srsName="EPSG:4326">
            <gml:lowerCorner>-124.535124 32.530795</gml:lowerCorner>
            <gml:upperCorner>-117.183631 42.000046</gml:upperCorner>
          </gml:Envelope>
        </gml:boundedBy>
        <dc:coverage rdf:resource="http://sws.geonames.org/3687919/" dc:language="eng" dc:title="California"/>
        <dc:coverage rdf:resource="http://sws.geonames.org/8411083/" dc:language="eng" dc:title="Pacific Ocean"/>
      </rdf:Description>
    </rdf:RDF>
  </extension>
<subject authority="EPSG" valueURI="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326" displayLabel="WGS84"><cartographics><scale>Scale not given.</scale><projection>EPSG::4326</projection><coordinates>W 124&#xB0;32&#x2B9;6&#x2BA;--W 117&#xB0;11&#x2B9;1&#x2BA;/N 42&#xB0;--N 32&#xB0;31&#x2B9;51&#x2BA;</coordinates></cartographics></subject><note displayLabel="WGS84 Cartographics">This layer is presented in the WGS84 coordinate system for web display purposes. Downloadable data are provided in native coordinate system or projection.</note></mods>
