<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" version="3.4" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Biotic Resources: Santa Cruz County, California, 2015</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <name type="personal">
    <namePart>Garcia, Paul</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name type="personal">
    <namePart>Price, Matt</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <typeOfResource>cartographic</typeOfResource>
  <typeOfResource>software, multimedia</typeOfResource>
  <genre authority="lcgft" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/genreForms/gf2011026297">Geospatial data</genre>
  <genre authority="rdacontent" valueURI="http://rdvocab.info/termList/RDAContentType/1001">cartographic dataset</genre>
  <originInfo>
    <publisher>County of Santa Cruz Information Services Department</publisher>
    <place>
      <placeTerm type="text">Santa Cruz, California, US</placeTerm>
    </place>
    <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes">2015</dateIssued>
    <dateValid encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateValid>
  </originInfo>
  <language>
    <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <physicalDescription>
    <form>Shapefile</form>
    <extent>4.516</extent>
    <digitalOrigin>born digital</digitalOrigin>
  </physicalDescription>
  <subject>
    <cartographics>
      <scale>Scale not given.</scale>
      <projection>EPSG::2227</projection>
      <coordinates>(W 122°19ʹ8ʺ--W 121°34ʹ53ʺ/N 37°16ʹ58ʺ--N 36°50ʹ32ʺ)</coordinates>
    </cartographics>
  </subject>
  <abstract displayLabel="Abstract" lang="eng">This polygon shapefile depicts biotic resource areas in the County of Santa Cruz, California. Biotic resources are designated due to their rare or especially valuable nature or role in an ecosystem and can be easily disturbed or degraded by human activity. Biotic Resources are protected and preserved for their genetic, scientific and educational values. This layer is part of a collection of GIS data created for Santa Cruz County, California.</abstract>
  <abstract displayLabel="Purpose" lang="eng">The Geographic Information Systems (GIS) Unit falls under the purview of the County of Santa Cruz Information Services Department. The GIS Unit serves all County departments and external customers and provides data on land, features and people of Santa Cruz County. Santa Cruz County encompasses 4 cities and approximately 265,000 people. This coverage can be used for basic applications such as viewing, querying and map output production, or to provide a basemap to support graphical overlays and analyses of geospatial data.</abstract>
  <note displayLabel="Preferred citation" lang="eng">County of Santa Cruz Information Services Department. (2015). Biotic Resources: Santa Cruz County, California, 2015. Santa Cruz County, California. Available at http://purl.stanford.edu/xg604dj4772.</note>
  <note displayLabel="Supplemental information">Biotic Resources as defined in General Plan adopted May 24, 1994 are areas defined as sensitive habitat meeting one of the following criterea: (a) Areas of special biological significance as identified by the State Water Resources Control Board. (b) Areas which provide habitat for locally unique biotic species/communities,including coastal scrub, maritime chaparral, native rhododendrons and associated Elkgrass, mapped grasslands in the coastal zone and sand parkland; and Special Forests including San Andreas Live Oak Woodlands, Valley Oak, Santa Cruz Cypress, indigenous Ponderosa Pine, indigenous Monterey Pine and ancientforests. (c) Areas adjacent to essential habitats of rare, endangered or threatened species as defined in (e) and (f) below. (d) Areas which provide habitat for Species of Special Concern as listed by the California Department of Fish and Game in the Special Animals list, Natural Diversity Database. (e) Areas which provide habitat for rare or endangered species which meet the definition of Section 15380 of the California Environmental Quality Act guidelines. (f) Areas which provide habitat for rare, endangered or threatened species as designated by the State Fish and Game Commission, United States Fish and Wildlife Service or California Native Plant Society. (g) Nearshore reefs, rocky intertidal areas, seacaves, islets, offshore rocks, kelp beds, marine mammal hauling grounds, sandy beaches, shorebird roosting, resting and nesting areas, cliff nesting areas and marine, wildlife or educational/research reserves. (h) Dune plant habitats. (i) All lakes, wetlands, estuaries, lagoons, streams and rivers. (j) Riparian corridors.

Santa Cruz County Sensitive Habitat Protection Code: http://www.codepublishing.com/ca/santacruzcounty/mobile/index.pl?pg=SantaCruzCounty16/SantaCruzCounty1632.html</note>
  <note displayLabel="Use limitation">These data were compiled from many different sources; therefore, the accuracy of the individual layers varies significantly, and some layers do not align exactly with others. In the urban areas, data are generally accurate within five to ten feet of their true geographic coordinates, but in the rural areas, data may be accurate to only within three hundred feet. With these limitations, the County of Santa Cruz disclaims any responsibility for the accuracy or correctness of this data. This disclaimer is exclusive and in lieu of any warranties, fitness for particular purpose, and/or any other type of warranty, whether expressed or implied.</note>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects" lang="eng">Ecosystem management</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects" lang="eng">Biotic communities</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="lcsh" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects" lang="eng">Habitat conservation</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic lang="eng">Santa Cruz County (Calif.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <temporal encoding="w3cdtf">2015</temporal>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="biota">Biology and Ecology</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic authority="ISO19115TopicCategory" authorityURI="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_TopicCategoryCode" valueURI="boundaries">Boundaries</topic>
  </subject>
  <location>
    <url>http://purl.stanford.edu/xg604dj4772</url>
  </location>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Stanford</recordContentSource>
    <recordIdentifier>edu.stanford.purl:xg604dj4772</recordIdentifier>
    <recordOrigin>This record was translated from ISO 19139 to MODS v.3 using an xsl transformation.</recordOrigin>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
  </recordInfo>
  <extension displayLabel="geo">
    <rdf:RDF xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml/3.2/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://purl.stanford.edu/xg604dj4772">
        <dc:format>application/x-esri-shapefile; format=Shapefile</dc:format>
        <dc:type>Dataset#Polygon</dc:type>
        <gml:boundedBy>
          <gml:Envelope gml:srsName="EPSG:4326">
            <gml:lowerCorner>-122.316694 36.848881</gml:lowerCorner>
            <gml:upperCorner>-121.582293 37.276125</gml:upperCorner>
          </gml:Envelope>
        </gml:boundedBy>
      </rdf:Description>
    </rdf:RDF>
  </extension>
  <subject authority="EPSG" valueURI="http://opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326" displayLabel="WGS84">
    <cartographics>
      <scale>Scale not given.</scale>
      <projection>EPSG::4326</projection>
      <coordinates>W 122°19ʹ--W 121°34ʹ56ʺ/N 37°16ʹ34ʺ--N 36°50ʹ56ʺ</coordinates>
    </cartographics>
  </subject>
  <note displayLabel="WGS84 Cartographics">This layer is presented in the WGS84 coordinate system for web display purposes. Downloadable data are provided in native coordinate system or projection.</note>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Santa Cruz County, California GIS Maps &amp; Data</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <location>
      <url>https://purl.stanford.edu/kn733hp1726</url>
    </location>
    <typeOfResource collection="yes"/>
  </relatedItem>
  <accessCondition type="useAndReproduction">This item is in the public domain.  There are no restrictions on use.</accessCondition>
</mods>
